MATT:
WE ARE HOVERING AROUND ALL-TIME
HIGHS FOR STOCKS.
DANI: "OPEN INTEREST"
STARTS RIGHT NOW.
MATT:
COMING UP, APPLE CAPS OFF A
MASSIVE WEEK FOR EARNINGS,
DELIVERING ITS SURPRISINGLY
STRONG OUTLOOK. DANI:
OIL WAIVERS ON A REPORT THAT
IRAN REPLIED ON A POTENTIAL
PEACE AGREEMENT.
MATT:
GM'S PIT -- JANE STREET'S PAY
POOL MORE THAN DOUBLED.
WE ARE SWIMMING IN CASH, BUT WE
NEED IT, BECAUSE GAS IS FOUR
DOLLARS AND $.30. DANI:
PEOPLE ARE STILL BUYING APPLE
PRODUCTS EVEN THOUGH IT IS MORE
EXPENSIVE FOR APPLE TO MAKE
THEM.
SHARES UP 2.2 PERCENT, POSTING
DOUBLE DIGIT SALES GROWTH AND
BETTER THAN EXPECTED REVENUE
FORECASTS.
THE CONCERN FOR THEM WAS THAT
THE COST OF HARDWARE, THE COST
OF MEMORY, WAS GOING UP.
THEY HAVE A SHORTAGE OF MAX.
-- MAS. -- MACS. MATT:
THEY COULD KEEP PRICING POWER.
CHEVRON AND EXXON EARNINGS
BLOWING PAST ESTIMATES AS OIL
PRICES AND PRODUCTION INCREASES
HELPED OFFSET SUPPLY CONCERNS
DUE TO THE WAR IN THE MIDDLE
EAST, WHICH IS ENTERING NOW ITS
THIRD MONTH, AND NO ONE IN THE
EQUITY MARKETS CARES.
7200 PLUS ON THE S&P 500.
THE VIX IS AT 16. DANI:
IT IS WILD.
PCE ACCELERATING 70 BASIS
POINTS IN A SINGLE MONTH.
A LOT OF PEOPLE JUST POINT TO
EARNINGS AND HOW ROBUST THIS
EARNINGS SEASON HAS BEEN.
APPLE ADDS TO THAT.
ED LUDLOW JOINS US NOW.
BLOWING PAST EXPECTATIONS. ED:
IT WAS SUCH A ON IN THE MOMENT
THING. SALES GROWING 14%.
NOT JUST THE STOCK CHANGED
TRAJECTORY.
THE ENTIRE SENTIMENT.
IT IS A CLEAR SITUATION FROM
APPLE'S POINT OF VIEW.
THEY WOULD SAY THAT DEMAND IS
GREATER THAN THEIR ABILITY TO
SUPPLY.
IT IS CHIPS GENERALLY THAT IS
THE CONSTRAINT, AND TIM COOK
TALKED ABOUT THE LACK OF
APPROPRIATE CAPACITY FOR CHIP
MANUFACTURING.
THE OIL PRICING ISSUE IS GOING
TO CONTINUE.
APPLE ARE THE MASTERS OF THE
BOTTOM LINE.
BUT TIM COOK DID NOT ACTUALLY
SAY THAT MUCH ABOUT WHAT THEY
COULD DO TO INSULATE FROM
ENERGY.
THERE IS A LACK OF SUPPLY OF
MAC AND IPHONE IN PARTICULAR.
OTHERWISE, STRENGTH.
CHINA WAS STRONG, AND SERVICES
CONTINUES TO ADD TO THAT GROWTH
STORY. MATT:
DID WE HEAR ANYTHING FROM THE
NEW GUY, BEYOND TIM WAS A GREAT
BOSS, THANK YOU SO MUCH, AND WE
ARE DOING INCREDIBLY WELL? ED:
EVERYONE IS AT THE KEYBOARD
LIKE WILL HE OR WON'T HE TURN
UP.
HE TURNS UP AND GOES I WANT TO
SAY VERY BRIEFLY THAT THERE IS
A GREAT PRODUCT ROADMAP.
THIS IS THE INCOMING CEO.
THEN SAID BUT I'M NOT GOING TO
TELL YOU ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
THE TAKE AWAY FOR ME -- THE
MAIN THING HE WAS TRYING TO GET
ACROSS WAS CONTINUITY.
REALLY PRAISING HOW TIM COOK
HAS BEEN ONE OF THE GREATEST
CEO'S OF ALL TIME, HE SAID.
THAT WAS THE WILL HE/WON'T HE
MOMENT, AND HE DID. DANI:
FOR THESE TECH COMPANIES, IT IS
REMARKABLE HOW A PRIVATE
COMPANY HAS BEEN ROLLING AROUND
THEIR SHARE PRICE.
OPENAI, THE TEAM SPEAKING TO
SARAH FRIER. WHAT DID WE LEARN?
ED: THE INTERVIEW LAST NIGHT.
SHE IS PUSHING BACK ON THAT
REPORTING FROM THE WALL STREET
JOURNAL THAT OPENAI IS NOT
MEETING ITS INTERNAL TARGETS.
WE FEEL LIKE WE ARE BEATING OUR
PLAN AT THE HIGHEST LEVEL, IS
THE OPENING.
SHE TALKS ABOUT HOW IN HER
CAREER AS A CFO, IT IS
IMPORTANT TO HAVE STRETCH GOALS.
OPENAI HAS STRETCH GOALS.
THE METRIC AT THE CENTER OF
THAT THIS WEEK WAS CHATGPT NOT
GETTING TO ONE BILLION ACTIVE
WEEKLY CHATGPT USERS.
SHE DID NOT ADDRESS THAT METRIC
SPECIFICALLY IN THE INTERVIEW
AT BLOOMBERG NEWS, BUT SAID
THEY ARE RUNNING AHEAD OF THEIR
HIGHEST EXPECTATIONS.
THE COATING AGENT IS NOW UP TO
4 MILLION WEEKLY USERS, AS AN
EXAMPLE. A SIMILAR STORY ON THE
SUPPLY/DEMAND EQUATION.
OPENAI HAS BEEN SAYING FOR
QUITE A LONG TIME IF THEY HAD
MORE COMPUTE CAPACITY --
ANXIETIES ABOUT HOW MUCH THEY
ARE SPENDING -- THEY WOULD BE
ABLE TO OFFER MORE FEATURES AND
WOULD SEE FASTER GROWTH.
SHE STUCK TO HER GUNS ON THAT
ONE. AN INTERESTING INTERVIEW.
I REALLY RECOMMEND THE AUDIENCE
GO AND READ THE FULL THING ON
THE TERMINAL. MATT:
DEFINITELY A GOOD READ.
THEY WANT TO SPEND $600 BILLION
THROUGH 2030 AND ARE LOOKING AT
ANNUAL REVENUE OF LIKE 25.
THEY HAVE GOT TO FIND THAT.
I LOOK FORWARD TO YOUR PROGRAM,
CONSIDERING HOW MUCH IS GOING
ON, AS IS THE CASE EVERY DAY IN
TECH, BUT ESPECIALLY TODAY.
BLOOMBERG TECH KICKS OFF AT 11
:00 A.M. WEEKDAYS.
CHEVRON AND EXXON ALSO BEAT
EARNINGS ESTIMATES.
HIGHER OIL AND GAS PRICES
OUTWEIGHED PRODUCTION OUTAGES
FROM THE IRAN WAR.
THEY ARE BRINGING MORE ONLINE
IN THE PERMIAN.
JOINING US IS THE BLOOMBERG OIL
REPORTER.
DAVID, SHARES ARE DOWN A LITTLE
BIT TODAY, BUT THEY HAVE BEEN
UP YEAR TO DATE.
REALLY A BRIGHT SPOT, I GUESS A
STRONG RESULT FROM THE WAR IN
IRAN. DAVID:
THE HIGH OIL PRICES ARE GOING
TO LIFT BOTH OF THESE
COMPANIES, JUST A MATTER OF
FACT.
A LITTLE MORE TRICKY FOR EXXON
THAN CHEVRON, BECAUSE EXXON IS
MORE AFFECTED BY THE STRAIT OF
HORMUZ CLOSURE.
ABOUT 15% OF ITS GLOBAL OIL
PRODUCTION IS OFF-LINE BECAUSE
OF THE STREET CLOSURE.
CHEVRON, LESS IMPACTED.
SOME IMPACT FROM THE STREET
CLOSURE AS WELL.
LOOK FOR BOTH COMPANIES TO TRY
TO USE THEIR GLOBAL FOOTPRINT
TO MANEUVER AND REPOSITION
AROUND THE WORLD TO TRY TO FILL
SOME OF THE GAP.
WE WILL WAIT TO LISTEN ON BOTH
CALLS ON HOW THEY TALK ABOUT
WHAT THE ULTIMATE IMPACTS WILL
BE, AND SORT OF WHAT THIS IS
GOING TO MEAN FOR THE GLOBAL
MARKET. DANI:
DO YOU THINK THERE MIGHT BE ANY
POLITICS AT PLAY, ANY OF THESE
EXECUTIVES CALLING ON THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION TO TRY TO MOVE
TO REOPEN THE STRAIT OF HORMUZ?
DO THEY HAVE THAT EAR OF THE
PRESIDENT, GIVEN THE CONCERN ON
AFFORDABILITY AND GAS PRICES IN
THIS COUNTRY? DAVID:
WE KNOW THEY HAVE A LINE TO THE
TRUMP ADMINISTRATION.
CHEVRON SAID RECENTLY THAT THEY
SPEAK WITH THE TRUMP
ADMINISTRATION REGULARLY.
YOU HAVE TO KNOW THAT THEY ARE
GETTING THEIR POINT ACROSS.
THEY ARE SAYING OPEN THE STRAIT
OF HORMUZ OR OTHER POLICY
THINGS, SUCH AS DO NOT BAN
EXPORTS. WE DON'T WANT TO LIMIT
SUPPLIES.
THEY MIGHT BE SAYING IT IN
OTHER WAYS.
THEY MIGHT ALSO BE TRYING TO
SAY THAT THEY NEED TO OPEN UP
AREAS LIKE VENEZUELA, AND TRY
TO GET OTHER OIL BARRELS OUT TO
OTHER PARTS OF THE WORLD.
THERE MAY BE A MIXTURE OF
DIFFERENT WAYS TO TRY TO GET TO
THE TRUMP ADMINISTRATION. DANI:
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
LATER ON, THE EXXON CFO WILL BE
JOINING THE TEAM.
THE REPORT OF BEING ON TRACK TO
BEAT FUNDRAISING GOALS.
EARNINGS DID MEET ESTIMATES,
BUT SHARES ARE UP 2.2%.
THE GLOBAL FINANCE EDITOR JOINS
US NOW.
IT HAS BEEN A TOUGH START TO
THE YEAR FOR AREAS.
I WONDER WHAT WE MAKE OF THE
FACT THAT THEY ARE STILL ABLE
TO BRING IN SO MUCH CASH,
DESPITE ALL OF THE HEADLINES.
>> IT IS A GOOD SIGN.
THERE ARE THE LINGERING WELLS
IN PRIVATE EQUITY.
IT IS A GOOD SIGN THAT
INVESTORS ARE NOT SHYING AWAY.
THAT WILL BE KEY AS WE GET INTO
THE NEXT WEEK.
WITH MILKEN, I THINK WE WILL BE
HEARING FROM EXECUTIVES ON
EXACTLY HOW IS IT LOOKING NOW.
ARE INVESTORS STILL WILLING TO
PUT MONEY INTO THESE PRIVATE
STRATEGIES?
SO FAR IT LOOKS LIKE FROM
ARIES, YES. MATT:
JANE STREET HOLDING $40 BILLION
IN TRADING REVENUE LAST YEAR.
OBVIOUSLY, THEY ARE PAYING
THEIR EMPLOYEES FOR DOING A
GREAT JOB. $10 BILLION?
>> I THINK IT IS A REAL SIGN.
JANE STREET ARE OUTRANKING
THEIR COMPETITORS.
THAT PAY, IF YOU WANT TO EQUATE
IT EVENLY -- IT IS NOT TOTALLY
DIVIDED UP.
IF YOU WERE TOO, THAT IS MORE
THAN SEVEN TIMES WHAT GOLDMAN
WORKERS GET.
IT IS A SHOCKING REMINDER OF
WHERE SOME OF THE POWER -- THE
SHIFTING INFLUENCE AND POWER IN
WALL STREET, REALLY. MATT:
FORMERLY OF JANE STREET AND
UNRELATED TO THIS -- SAM
BANKMAN-FRIED'S INVESTMENTS
HAVE BEEN ON FIRE.
IF HE BILKED INVESTORS OUT OF
BILLIONS OF DOLLARS -- DANI:
WITH OPENAI AND ANTHROPIC. MATT:
IT IS INCREDIBLE.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
CATHERINE COVERS THESE FINANCE
TITANS FOR US.
CHECK ON WHAT IS GOING ON IN
THE MARKETS AFTER WE CLOSE AT
AN ALL-TIME HIGH YESTERDAY.
WE ARE LOOKING AT GAINS IN
FUTURES.
NASDAQ FUTURES NOT DOING QUITE
AS WELL.
BUT THAT INDEX HAS BEEN ON FIRE
THE 10 YEAR YIELD FLOATS HIGHER.
ANOTHER 1.5 BASIS POINTS TODAY,
AND WE ARE GETTING CLOSER TO
4.40 ON THE 10 YEAR, NEAR THE
NATURAL -- NATIONAL AVERAGE FOR
GAS. THOSE PRICES ARE STILL
ELEVATED, BUT IT DOES NOT SEEM
TO BE AFFECTING EARNINGS
EXPECTATIONS OR S&P VALUATIONS.
ROBLOX SHARES ARE DOWN AFTER
IMPLEMENTING SAFETY FEATURES
THAT ENDED UP SLOWING USER
GROWTH.
DANI:
ESTEE LAUDER PLANNING TO CUT UP
TO 3000 MORE JOBS.
THANK GOD THEY DID NOT DO SOME
WEIRD AI THING OR SOMETHING
LIKE THAT. MATT:
MODERNA SHARES MORE THAN
TRIPLED FROM A YEAR AGO, FUELED
BY DEALS WITH GOVERNMENTS
OUTSIDE THE U.S..
YOU CAN SEE MODERNA UP 3% IN
THE PREMARKET.
TUNE IN TO THE CLOSE AT 3:00
P.M.
TO HEAR FROM THE CEO OF THAT
COMPANY. DANI:
COMING UP, DAY 60 OF THE IRAN
WAR.
A KEY LEGAL DEADLINE HITS WITH
TRUMP'S WAR POWERS ON THE LINE.
MATT: LET'S GET A LOOK AT HIGH
INTEREST -- WHAT IS MOVING
HEADLINES AROUND THE WORLD.
TESLA TALLIED UP ELON MUSK'S
ANNUAL COMPENSATION FOR THE
FIRST TIME SINCE ANALYST --
SINCE INVESTORS APPROVED'S PAY
PACKAGE.
158 BILLION DOLLARS ON PAPER,
BUT THERE IS A CATCH.
ZERO DOLLARS IN ACTUAL PAY
BECAUSE TESLA MISSED KEY
TARGETS AND THE PAY PACKAGE
DEPENDS ON PERFORMANCE GOALS.
A PROPOSED NYC TAX SPARKING A
BILLIONAIRE BACKLASH.
IT DREW CRITICISM FROM WALL
STREET ELITES WHO SAY THE TONE,
NOT THE TAX, IS THE PROBLEM.
GRIFFIN IS WEIGHING INVESTMENT
PULLBACKS AS THE CITY AIMS TO
RAISE 500 MILLION DOLLARS.
GRIFFIN MET WITH NEW YORK
GOVERNOR KATHY HOCHUL YESTERDAY
TO DISCUSS THE TAX PROPOSAL.
FARMERS ARE INCREASINGLY
REFUSING TO ANSWER USDA
SURVEYS, WITH RESPONSE RATES
DROPPING FROM ABOUT 60% EIGHT
YEARS AGO TO JUST OVER ONE
THIRD THIS YEAR.
GROWERS SAY THE REPORTS ARE
BASED ON UNRUSHED, UNRELIABLE
DATA. THE USDA WARNS THE LACK OF
REPLY IT WILL WEAKEN ACCURACY,
FUELING MORE DISTRUST.
OFFICIALS ARE LOOKING AT WAYS
TO REBUILD COMPETENCE AS A
SHAKY DATA BEGINS TO RIPPLE
THROUGH GLOBAL CROP MARKETS.
DANI: IRAN REPLIED TO U.S.
AMENDMENTS ON THE DEAL TO END
THE WAR.
DOES THIS GET US CLOSER TO
TALKS, TO MORE CEASE FIRE, TO
PEACE, TO ANYTHING?
>> PERHAPS SOME POTENTIAL
PROGRESS. WE DON'T HAVE FURTHER
INFORMATION BEYOND THAT IRAN
SENT AN AMENDED PROPOSAL TO THE
U.S. REQUESTS, THROUGH PAKISTANI
MEDIATORS. WE KNOW THE U.S.
WAS NOT HAPPY WITH THE PLAN
IRAN HAD PREVIOUSLY PUT ON THE
TABLE, WHICH WOULD POSTPONE ANY
DIALOGUE ABOUT ITS NUCLEAR
PROGRAM IN EXCHANGE FOR PERHAPS
AN INTERNAL DEAL WHERE WE COULD
SEE A REOPENING OF THE STRAIT
OF HORMUZ IN EXCHANGE FOR THE
U.S. LIFTING ITS NAVAL BLOCKADE.
BUT WHITE HOUSE OFFICIALS MADE
IT CLEAR THAT ANY AGREEMENT
NEEDS TO INCLUDE CURBS ON
IRAN'S NUCLEAR CAPABILITIES,
AND THE BLOCKADE LEVERAGE IS
NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
PRESIDENT TRUMP CALLED THE
BLOCKADE INCREDIBLE. THE U.S.
IS DOUBLING DOWN.
A SENIOR ADMINISTRATION
OFFICIAL TELLS US THAT THE
DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE HAS
IMPLEMENT IT A PROCESS FOR TWO
IRANIAN LINKED OIL TANKERS THAT
WERE SEIZED BY U.S.
NAVAL FORCES THE OTHER WEEK.
IT IS NOT CLEAR WHAT THIS WILL
ENTAIL, BUT IT IS SOMETHING TO
WATCH BECAUSE IT COULD SIGNAL
INTENT TO SEIZE THE OIL CARGOES
ON BOARD, WHICH WOULD BE
CONSIDERED ESCALATION.
THAT IS NOT THE ONLY ESCALATION.
THERE IS ALWAYS THE RISK FOR
MORE ESCALATION, AS AXIOS
REPORTED YESTERDAY THAT
PRESIDENT TRUMP WAS BRIEFED
ABOUT AN ARRAY OF OPTIONS
INCLUDING THE POTENTIAL FOR A
SHORT WAVE OF STRIKES THAT
COULD MAYBE HELP BREAK WHAT HAS
BEEN A DEADLOCK IN THE
DISCUSSIONS.
WHEN HE WAS ASKED YESTERDAY IF
HE WAS GETTING ANTSY AND IF YOU
WANTED TO END THE CEASE-FIRE,
RESUME MILITARY OPERATIONS,
PRESIDENT TRUMP SAID THAT AT
THIS POINT NOBODY REALLY KNOWS
WHERE THE NEGOTIATION STAND,
BEYOND HIM AND A FEW KEY
ADVISORS, ADDING THAT HE HAS
BLAMED A LACK OF PROGRESS IN
THE TALKS ON FRACTURED
LEADERSHIP IN IRAN. MATT:
PETE HEGSETH WOULD ARGUE WE ARE
NOT STILL IN A WAR BECAUSE OF
THE CEASE-FIRE.
HE IS A MAN WHO I THINK PRIDES
HIMSELF ON HIS KNOWLEDGE OF
MILITARY TRADITION, AND
TRADITIONALLY, A BLOCKADE IS AN
ACT OF WAR, ALSO CONSIDERED SO
UNDER INTERNATIONAL LAW.
WHY DOESN'T THE ADMINISTRATION
WANT CONGRESS, THE
REPRESENTATIVES OF THE AMERICAN
PEOPLE, TO BE ABLE TO WEIGH IN
ON SUCH AN IMPORTANT EVENT, A
WAR IN THE MIDDLE EAST THAT HAS
DOUBLED THE PRICE OF OIL? TYLER:
IT IS A REALLY GOOD POINT
CONSIDERING WE ARE AT THAT 60
DAY MARK WHICH UNDER THE WAR
POWERS WOULD MEAN THE PRESIDENT
NEEDS TO SEEK AUTHORIZATION
FROM CONGRESS TO CONTINUE THE
HOSTILITIES OR AT LEAST REQUEST
A 30 DAY EXTENSION TO SAFELY
WITHDRAW THE TROOPS.
THERE IS CHATTER IN WASHINGTON
AND SPECULATION THAT MAY BE THE
ADMINISTRATION IS GOING TO ASK
FOR THAT 30 DAY EXTENSION, BUT
AS YOU ALLUDED TO, IT DOES NOT
SEEM THEY'RE GOING TO DO THAT
ANYTIME SOON, BECAUSE SECRETARY
PETE HEGSETH IS ARGUING THE 60
DAY COUNTDOWN CLOCK HAS BEEN
HALTED AMID THIS CEASE-FIRE.
DEMOCRATS ON CAPITOL HILL WOULD
ARGUE THAT THEY ARE STILL VERY
MUCH ENGAGED IN HOSTILITIES,
AND THEY WANT TO SEE CURBS PUT
ON THIS WAR BY MEMBERS OF THE
U.S. CONGRESS.
BUT JUST YESTERDAY, WE SAW WHAT
I BELIEVE IS THE 10TH MEASURE
FAILED THAT WOULD DO JUST THAT.
WE CAN SAY THAT FOR THE FIRST
TIME YOU SAW REPUBLICANS -- ONE
REPUBLICAN ACROSS PARTY LINES
AND CHANGE THEIR VOTE WHEN IT
COMES TO SUPPORTING THIS WAR,
AND THAT WAS REPUBLICAN SENATOR
SUSAN COLLINS.
PERHAPS WE WILL SEE FUTURE
PRESSURE WHEN IT DOES COME TO
THIS, BECAUSE WE CAN SAY AT
LEAST AT THIS POINT THAT THERE
HAS BEEN SOME MURMURANCE FROM
OTHER REPUBLICAN LAWMAKERS THAT
THEY ARE IN SUPPORT OF TRUMP'S
MILITARY OPERATION.
WHEN IT COMES TO THE
ADMINISTRATION ASKING FOR MORE
FUNDING, WHEN WE SEE THAT
SUPPLEMENTAL REQUEST FOR THE
PENTAGON SPECIFICALLY WHEN IT
COMES TO THE WAR IN IRAN, NOT
THE SEPARATE FISCAL YEAR BUDGET
REQUEST, I WOULD EXPECT TO SEE
MORE REPUBLICAN SPEAK UP THAT
THEY WOULD LIKE TO HAVE
CONGRESS HAVE A SAY IN HOW THIS
WAR IS GOING TO GO FORWARD.
DANI: THAT IS TYLER KENDALL IN
WASHINGTON.
COMING UP, AI MONETIZATION IS
FINALLY TAKING SHAPE AFTER
COMPANY SPENT TRILLIONS ON
GROWTH.
ANASTASIA AMOROSO JOINS US NEXT.
♪
DANI: ANASTASIA AMOROSO SAYS ONE
EARNINGS STATEMENT SUMMED UP
THE AI MOMENT IN MARKETS.
IN ITS EARNINGS RELEASE, THE
AMAZON CEO SAID THREE YEARS
AFTER AWS LAUNCHED, IT HAD 58
MILLION DOLLARS REVENUE RUN
RATE.
IN THE FIRST THREE YEARS OF
THIS AI WAVE, THE AWS REVENUE
RUN RATE IS OVER $15 BILLION,
NEARLY 216 TIMES LARGER.
ANASTASIA AMOROSO JOINS US NOW.
I GUESS THIS KIND OF FIGHTS
BACK AGAINST THIS IDEA THAT THE
PROOF OF AI IS NOT HERE.
BUT IT IS HERE.
BUT COMPANIES LIKE META SELL
OFF AFTER THEIR EARNINGS WITH
SHAKINESS. ANASTASIA:
THERE IS SOME DIFFERENTIATION
BETWEEN WHO IS REALLY
BENEFITING FROM ARTIFICIAL
INTELLIGENCE AND WHO IS AT THE
FOREFRONT OF THE BENEFIT -- OF
BEING THE BENEFICIARY ARE THE
COMPANY SELLING CLOUD CAPACITY
TO GENAI COMPANIES THAT ARE
SEEING MODERN -- SEE
MODERNIZATION AS WELL.
CLOUD REVENUE IS EXPECTED TO
GROW BY 23% THIS YEAR.
I THINK WE NEED TO UPSIZE THAT
NUMBER AFTER THE REPORTING
SEASON.
FAST-FORWARD TO 2020 NINE.
IF YOU LOOK AT SOME OF THE
ESTIMATES FOR CLOUD REVENUES
FROM THE BIG FOUR, IT STEPS UP
TO SOMETHING LIKE 700 BILLION
DOLLARS, SO IT IS MEANINGFUL.
MANY INVESTORS HAVE BEEN
WAITING FOR THE PAYOFF, BUT I
DO THINK IT IS GOING TO COME
OVER A SEQUENCE OF YEARS. MATT:
I READ THROUGH YOUR NOTES AND
THE BIG NUMBER TO ME IS $1.5
TRILLION.
THAT IS THE AMOUNT OF BASICALLY
AI BACKLOG THAT YOU HAVE
CALCULATED FROM BASICALLY THE
FOUR BIG HYPERSCALERS.
IT IS A MASSIVE AMOUNT.
TELL US ABOUT THE NUMBER, HOW
YOU GOT TO IT. ANASTASIA:
THE COMPANIES THEMSELVES STATED
THAT CLOUD REVENUES TODAY --
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF
CONTRACTED REVENUES THAT ARE
NOT YET RECOGNIZED IN THE
CURRENT NUMBERS.
THAT GOES BACK TO THE POINT
THAT INVESTORS OFTEN ASK ISN'T
ALL OF THIS PRICED IN IT.
THE REALITY IS WHAT IS PRICED
IN IS THE NEXT QUARTER.
BUT TYPICALLY WHAT IS NOT
PRICED IN IS THE NEXT COUPLE OF
YEARS. I THINK THAT IS WHAT THE
BACKLOG SPEAKS TO.
THAT IS WHY WE SEE THAT 2029
UPSIDE. DANI:
IS IT HARD TO PRICE IN?
HUGE NUMBERS AND UNCERTAINTY.
HOW MUCH CONVICTION DO YOU HAVE
AROUND THESE?
THESE THINGS ARE CHANGING SO
RAPIDLY. ANASTASIA:
THEY ARE, BUT MAYBE THAT IS THE
WHOLE POINT.
AI IS ACCELERATING PAST, AS THE
AMAZON CEO PUT IT, AN
UNPRECEDENTED PACE.
TODAY, WE ARE AT 55 PERCENT
ADOPTION, AI, MEANING 55% OF
U.S. ADULTS USE SOME SORT OF AI
APPLICATION.
IF YOU CONTRAST THAT TO
INTERNET ADOPTION OR PERSONAL
COMPUTER ADOPTION, THREE YEARS
INTO THE ADOPTION CURVE, WE ARE
AT 19% ADOPTION FOR PERSONAL
COMPUTERS AND ABOUT 30% FOR THE
INTERNET. CASE IN POINT, THIS IS
ACCELERATING PRETTY
SIGNIFICANTLY.
TO YOUR POINT, HOW DO WE KNOW
THIS IS TRULY GOING TO COME
THROUGH?
WE SEE AN INCREASED NUMBER OF
AI TOOLS BEING LAUNCHED.
BUT THE SECOND THING IS IF YOU
LOOK AT THE REVENUES OF SOME OF
THE GENAI COMPANIES.
THIS YEAR, I BELIEVE THEY ARE
FORECASTING SOMETHING LIKE 54
BILLION DOLLARS IN REVENUES.
IN 2030, THEY ARE FORECASTING
$307 BILLION. MATT:
ANASTASIA AMOROSO STICKING
AROUND. THE OPENING BELT NEXT.
ALL-TIME RECORD HIGH OF STOCKS YESTERDAY. ♪
MATT:
WE ARE MOMENTS AWAY FROM THE
START OF TRADING.
THIS IS "OPEN INTEREST." WE ARE
LOOKING AT FUTURES THAT ARE
HIGHER AFTER CLOSING OVER 7200
ON THE S&P 500 YESTERDAY.
RIGHT NOW, THIS MARKET, YOU CAN
SEE FUTURES UP ZERO POINT 3% ON
THE S&P.
COMPLETELY UNDETERRED AND
REALLY NOT INTERESTED IN A WAR
THAT IS EXTENDING INTO A THIRD
MONTH, CREATED PRICES THAT HAVE
DOUBLED.
PCE AT THE CORE IS 3.2 PERCENT,
SO 60% ABOVE THE FED TARGET AND
CLIMBING.
DOES NOT MATTER BECAUSE WE HAVE
LOW JOBLESS CLAIMS RIGHT NOW.
WE HAVE GREAT EARNINGS.
AND WE HAVE 1.5 TRILLION DOLLAR
BACKLOG IN TERMS OF AI, THE CAP
EXPLOITING EVERYBODY AWAY.
KKR READING THE BELL AT --
RINGING THE BELL AT THE NEW
YORK STOCK EXCHANGE.
HENRY KRAVIS AND THE TEAM.
GEORGE ROBERTS, HIS COUSIN,
CELEBRATING 50 YEARS, I GUESS.
DANI:
THE CEO'S, ABSOLUTE LEGENDS,
GATHERED. MATT:
ABSOLUTE TITANS OF WALL STREET.
THESE ARE THE BARBARIANS AT THE
GATE. VERY COOL.
I WAS LOOKING AT KKR STOCK.
OBVIOUSLY, THIS YEAR HAS BEEN A
TOUGH. NOT SO BAD. DOWN 20%.
BUT IT HAS DOUBLED OVER THE
LAST FIVE YEARS.
ANYTIME I CAN GET A RETURN LIKE
THAT, I WOULD BE HAPPY. DANI:
MAYBE SENTIMENT IS STARTING TO
CHANGE.
PRIVATE CREDIT WEIGHING ON
SHARES. IN THE MEANTIME, APPLE
RECORDING YESTERDAY AFTER THE
BELL. IT IS UP 4%.
DOUBLE DIGIT SALES GROWTH.
A BETTER THAN EXPECTED REVENUE
FORECAST. ALL OF THAT DESPITE
RISING MEMORY COSTS FOR
HARDWARE, AND THEY HAVE LIMITED
OUTPUT.
SO THERE IS SUPPLY CONSTRAINT,
BUT PLENTY OF DEMAND.
SHARES HIGHER THIS MORNING.
MATT: FASCINATING EARNINGS.
WE ALSO SAW LESS UNEXPECTED --
CHEVRON AND EXXON DOING VERY
WELL.
THEY DID GO PAST ESTIMATES --
BLEW PAST THE ESTIMATES BECAUSE
OF OIL PRICES.
AND PRODUCTION INCREASES THAT
ARE OFFSETTING SUPPLY CONCERNS
OUT OF THE MIDDLE EAST. IT
LOOKS LIKE INVESTORS ARE TAKING
PROFIT HERE IN CHEVRON AND
EXXON BECAUSE THE OIL PATCH HAS
GAINED ABOUT 25% YEAR-TO-DATE.
LET'S BRING BACK THE PARTNERS
GROUP PRIVATE WEALTH CHIEF
INVESTMENT STRATEGIST,
ANASTASIA AMOROSO.
I'M ALWAYS CURIOUS TO KNOW YOUR
VIEWS ON HIGHER ENERGY PRICES.
IT HAS HELPED A BIG SECTOR OF
THE MARKET.
NOT A HUGELY WEIGHTED SECTOR ON
THE S&P.
IT IS BIG ON THE FTSE AND OTHER
INDEXES.
WHAT DO YOU THINK ABOUT HIGHER
OIL PRICES? ANASTASIA:
HIGHER OIL PRICES FOR NOW ARE
MANAGEABLE.
THIS WILL IMPACT THE MARGIN,
BUT THE U.S.
SHOULD REMAIN RESILIENT.
NO RECESSION IN THE CARDS.
THE REASON I SAY THAT IS FIRST
OF ALL THERE IS THE OVERALL
INTENSITY OF THE ECONOMY, WHICH
IS 6.3% LOWER THAN IN THE
1970'S.
I ALSO DON'T THINK THE FED WILL
RESPOND WITH RATE HIKES, WHICH
IS A KEY DIFFERENTIATOR.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE CONSUMER,
THERE ARE HIGHER GASOLINE
PRICES, BUT AT THE SAME TIME
ENERGY REPRESENTS 5% OR 6% OF
THE CPI BASKET.
SOMETHING LIKE 2% OF ACTUAL
HOUSEHOLD SPENDING.
FOR THOSE REASONS AND THE FACT
THAT WE HAVE BY AND LARGE
ENERGY INDEPENDENCE IN THE
U.S., THAT IS WHY WE REMAIN
RESILIENT. MATT:
WHAT CAN ENERGY INDEPENDENCE DO
FOR US GIVEN THAT THE PRICE OF
CRUDE IS SET GLOBALLY?
IT DOES NOT MATTER HOW MUCH
WEST TEXAS INTERMEDIATE WE ARE
PULLING OUT OF THE GROUND.
EVERYONE WHO IS A CONSUMER HAS
TO PAY THE SAME THAT PEOPLE IN
ASIA OR EUROPE ARE PAYING.
ANASTASIA:
I WOULD SAY A COUPLE OF THINGS.
FIRST OF ALL, IT PREVENTS
PHYSICAL SHORTAGES.
IF YOU ARE IN CHINA OR IN PARTS
OF ASIA, YOU MIGHT HAVE TO
THINK ABOUT ACTUAL PHYSICAL
SHORTAGE.
THAT IS WHY IN CHINA AND PARTS
OF EUROPE WE HAVE SEEN DEMAND
RESTRICTIONS.
WE HAVE NOT SEEN THAT IN THE
U.S.
PRICES ARE HIGHER, BUT WE DO
NOT HAVE PHYSICAL SHORTAGES.
THERE IS THE OIL SIDE OF
THINGS, BUT THERE IS THE
NATURAL GAS SIDE.
IF YOU LOOK AT NATURAL GAS
PRICES, PRICES A COUPLE OF
WEEKS AGO WERE BELOW WHERE THEY
WERE BEFORE THE WAR.
THAT IS WHAT ENERGY
INDEPENDENCE DOES, MAKING SURE
THAT ALL THE THINGS WE ARE
TRYING TO FUND, WHETHER IT IS
TO POWER DATA CENTERS OR
PREVENT PHYSICAL SHORTAGES.
DANI: ONE OF THE THINGS THAT WAS
FLAGGED BY THE QUANT TEAM AT
BLOOMBERG WAS THIS INDEX THAT
IS BASICALLY UNPROFITABLE
COMPANIES, BUT THE TRAJECTORY
IS SUCH THAT IT LOOKS LIKE THEY
WILL BE PROFITABLE.
AND IT IS TRADING AT ALL-TIME
HIGHS.
THIS IS THE INDEX RIGHT HERE.
THIS SEEMS LIKE A REALLY
BULLISH CONTOUR OF THE MARKET
BECAUSE IT IS NOT JUST
UNPROFITABLE COMPANIES, BUT
UNPROFITABLE COMPANIES THAT ARE
IMPROVING.
WHAT IS IT ABOUT THIS ECONOMY,
DESPITE THE FACT THAT OIL
PRICES ARE HIGHER, THAT
SENTIMENT IS REALLY LOW, THAT
UNPROFITABLE COMPANIES ARE
REACHING ALL-TIME HIGHS?
ANASTASIA:
KIND OF BROADLY FIRST AND THEN
MORE SPECIFIC TO THE INDEX -- I
MENTION THE CONSUMER BEING
RESILIENT.
BUT ALSO, YOU HAVE A PICKUP
INCORPORATE CAP.
WE TALK ABOUT HYPERSCALE CAPEX,
BUT BROADLY PICKED UP
SUBSTANTIALLY THIS YEAR.
YOU HAVE A SHIFTING OF CAPITAL
EXPENDITURES FROM SOFTWARE TO
HARDWARE.
SO ALL OF A SUDDEN YOU HAVE
THIS MANUFACTURING AND
INDUSTRIAL ENGINE THAT IS ALSO
WORKING FOR THE ECONOMY.
YOU HAVE PROFITABILITY FOR
LARGE CORPORATIONS WHICH IS AT
A RECORD HIGH.
WE ARE OUTPERFORMING IN TERMS
OF THE EARNINGS SEASON.
88% OF COMPANIES ARE BEATING
ESTIMATES BY SOMETHING LIKE
10%, 15%.
AND YOU HAVE A RECORD PROFIT
MARGIN.
IT IS NOT REPRESENTATIVE OF THE
ENTIRE ECONOMY, BUT I THINK IT
IS REPRESENTATIVE OF LARGE
DRIVERS OF THE ECONOMY.
THE INDEX IN PARTICULAR, I AM
CURIOUS TO SEE WHAT THE
COMPOSITION IS, BUT IT IS A
GOOD SIGN, AND IT IS A NATURAL,
THAT YOU START WITH AN
UNPROFITABLE COMPANY.
IF IT DOES HAVE THE RIGHT
SECULAR TRAJECTORY AND ECONOMIC
TAILWINDS, IT CAN MOVE INTO
PROFITABILITY. MATT:
I REMEMBER SO MANY PEOPLE
SAYING THAT IN 1999.
I KNOW THIS IS DIFFERENT, RIGHT?
DANI: TO BE FAIR, THE INDEX IS
DIFFERENT THINGS -- BLOOM
ENERGY, MACRON. WAYFAIR.
WARNER BROS. IS IN HERE.
IT FEELS REALLY DIVERSE IN THE
TYPE OF COMPANIES.
THERE IS A LOT OF TECH, BUT IT
FEELS LIKE A WIDE GROUP OF
INDUSTRY SUCCEEDING. ANASTASIA:
IT DOES TELL YOU THAT SOMETHING
IS WORKING IN THE U.S. ECONOMY.
SOME OF IT IS CYCLICAL, BUT
SOME OF IT IS SECULAR.
WE ARE STILL IN THE FIRST WAVE
OF A THREE WAVE TRANSFORMATION
FOR ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE,
AND THAT IS GOING TO PRODUCE A
LOT OF BENEFICIARIES IN DATA
CENTERS -- DATA SECTORS, THE
POWER SECTOR, THE SOFTWARE
SECTOR.
BLOOM ENERGY WAS IN THERE.
BACK TO THE ENERGY
CONVERSATION, A MONTH OR TWO
AGO, A LOT OF PEOPLE WOULD HAVE
TOLD YOU THE STRAIT OF HORMUZ
IS NEVER GOING TO SHUT DOWN OR
IS NOT GOING TO STAY SHUT FOR
MORE THAN A WEEK AGO. MATT:
OR IT WOULD BE CATASTROPHIC IF
IT DID. ANASTASIA:
THE MEMORY IS NOT GOING TO BE
SHORT ON THIS.
A LOT OF INVESTORS WILL THINK
WHAT DO WE NEED TO INVEST IN
GOING FORWARD. RESILIENCE.
LIKELY DOMESTIC ENERGY
INFRASTRUCTURE THAT IS
DIVERSIFIED AND POWERED BY
MULTIPLE SOURCES TO PRODUCE
ELECTRICITY.
DEPENDING ON WHERE YOU ARE.
MATT: GREAT HAVING YOU HERE.
THANK YOU SO MUCH.
YOU BRING US GREAT INTEL ALL
THE TIME.
ANASTASIA AMOROSO FROM PARTNERS
GROUP.
LET'S GET A CHECK ON THE STOCK
MARKET RIGHT NOW.
WE ARE LOOKING AT GAINS ONCE
AGAIN, UP HALF A PERCENT.
7247, THE LEVEL ON THE S&P.
THE BREADTH IS ALWAYS
INTERESTING TO LOOK AT.
IT IS STRONG TO THE UPSIDE.
THREE-TWO, GAINERS TO LOSERS
RIGHT NOW.
APPLE CONTINUES TO RISE AT 3.3
PERCENT AFTER BEATING
EXPECTATIONS YESTERDAY.
YOU HAVE MICROSOFT AND NVIDIA
ON THE UPSIDE AS WELL BEFORE
YOU GET OUT OF TECH AND INTO
DRUGS.
GOOGLE ON THE DOWNSIDE, BUT NOT
BY TOO MUCH, DOWN BY ABOUT 1%.
ANGEN OFF ABOUT FOUR POINT 5%.
LET'S LOOK AT THE INDUSTRIAL
BREAKDOWN OF THIS ON THE GRR
SCREEN RIGHT NOW.
YOU CAN SEE I T IS DOING WELL,
WHICH IS INTERESTING, WITH THE
NASDAQ AS WELL AS THE S&P 500.
THE REASON FOR THAT IS
COMMUNICATION SERVICES, AND THE
ENERGY INDEX IS THE BIGGEST
LOSER OF THE GROUP AFTER
BEATING EARNINGS.
WE USED TO SAY IT BY THE ROOM
OR AND SELL THE NEWS.
PERHAPS THAT IS WHAT IS
HAPPENING TODAY. DANI:
IT ALSO LOOKS LIKE A GOOD DAY
FOR SOFTWARE.
AT LAST AGAIN -- ATLASSIAN HAD
EARNINGS. MATT:
AND YOU HAD A GREAT
CONVERSATION WITH A MAN WHO
LOANS MONEY TO PRIVATE SOFTWARE
COMPANIES. DANI:
AND AS YOU MENTION, VERY
BULLISH. KIND OF HAS TO BE.
COMING UP, MAG SEVEN EARNINGS
SHOW AI DEMAND AND SPENDING IS
NOT LETTING UP AS IT POWERS THE
S&P 500 TO ALL-TIME HIGHS.
THIS IS "OPEN INTEREST." ♪
DANI: LET'S GET YOU SOME OF THE
ANALYST ACTION WE ARE WATCHING
THIS MORNING.
HERSHEY GETS AN UPGRADE AFTER
BEATING EXPECTATIONS.
THE CHOCOLATE COMPANY SAYS
OZEMPIC USERS ARE BUYING
GOVERNMENT FOR SIDE EFFECTS
LIKE BAD BREATH.
THERE IS NO WAY THAT OFFSETS
LOWER SALES FOR CHOCOLATE. MATT:
DRY MOUTH IS A SIDE EFFECT OF
GLP-1'S? DANI: AND BAD BREATH.
MATT:
ANYWAY, MORGAN STANLEY IS OUT
WITH A BIG UPGRADE ON
CATERPILLAR AS IT MORE THAN
DOUBLES ITS PRICE TARGET ON THE
COMPANY SAYING THAT RISING
DEMAND FOR DATA CENTERS IS
DRIVING STRONG GROWTH.
WHO WOULD HAVE THOUGHT.
WE ACTUALLY HAVE BEEN TALKING
ABOUT IT FOR A WHILE.
IT ADMITS IT UNDERESTIMATED
CONSTRUCTION DEMAND. DANI:
IPHONE DEMAND AND SOLID MARGINS
SHOW THAT APPLE IS HANDLING
COST PRESSURES
BETTER-THAN-EXPECTED. MATT:
STAYING WITH TECH, CITADEL
STRATEGIST TALKED ABOUT RECENT
MARKET VOLATILITY.
HE HAD THIS TO SAY. SCOTT:
RIGHT NOW, IT IS A BUYING
OPPORTUNITY, ESPECIALLY IN THE
U.S. MEGA TECH STOCKS. MATT:
LET'S BRING IN OUR SENIOR
ANALYST. A FANTASTIC DAY AT THE
BLOOMBERG HOUSE IN MIAMI, DANI
AND I BEATING THE DRONE TO THE
RACE BUT THEN LEAVING TOWN
BEFORE THE RACE HAPPENED.
I DON'T KNOW HOW THAT HAPPENED.
WHAT IS YOUR TAKE ON TECH AND
SOFTWARE STOCKS ON A DAY WHEN
WE HAVE FINISHED A BLOWOUT WEEK
IN EARNINGS FOR THE BIGGEST
HYPERSCALERS AND MAG 7
COMPANIES?
>> YOU SHOULD GO BUY SOME
COMPANIES BECAUSE THAT WOULD
REALLY HELP THE SECTOR AT THIS
POINT.
ON THE SOFTWARE SIDE, ATLASSIAN
DID WELL AND THAT IS HELPING.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT OTHER TECH
PROVIDERS AND EVEN APPLE, YOU
CAN SEE THE BIG DIVERGENCE
BETWEEN WHAT THEY ARE DOING
VERSUS WHAT THE REST OF THE
ECONOMY IS DOING.
WHEN WE LOOK AT TECHNOLOGY
COMPANIES THAT ARE NOT THESE
FOUR OR FIVE CLOUD PROVIDERS,
THEY ARE SEEING PRESSURE ON I.T.
SPENDING, WHETHER THAT IS
SERVICE, SALESFORCE.
THESE CLOUD PROVIDERS, BECAUSE
OF THEIR AI INFRASTRUCTURE,
THEY ARE SEEING A BOOST, AND
THEY ARE DOING A PHENOMENAL JOB
OF MANAGING EXPENSES, WHICH IS
SHOWING UP ON MARGINS.
IT IS A GREAT PLACE TO BE IN
TERMS OF A SECULAR GROWTH STORY.
DANI: EARNINGS PUNISHING ALL THE
SHORT-SELLERS THIS MORNING.
I KNEW YOU WERE LISTENING.
YOU DID MESSAGE ME.
HERE IS A TAKE IN TERMS OF THE
STRATEGY OF AI VERSUS SOFTWARE.
THE LINES GETTING MORE BLURRED.
TAKE A LISTEN. SCOTT:
-- ORLANDO:
AT THE MANY INDUSTRIES ARE
BECOMING SOFTWARE COMPANIES.
WITH AI, THEY ARE BECOMING
INTELLIGENT SOFTWARE.
WHEN YOU INVEST IN THESE
SPACES, WE CAN MOVE WITH THE
INDUSTRY ITSELF.
WHAT PEOPLE ARE MISSING IS THE
BEAUTY ABOUT SOFTWARE AND AI --
THEY WILL COME TOGETHER.
THERE WILL BE NO DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN EITHER IN THE NEXT
COUPLE OF YEARS. DANI:
ONE OF HIS BIG ARGUMENTS WAS
ESSENTIALLY THAT FOR THE BIG
FOUNDATIONAL MODELS, THEY NEED
FTES, ENGINEERS WHO CAN EMBED
WITH COMPANIES.
THEY ARE EXPENSIVE.
THEY TAKE TIME AND EFFORT.
INSTEAD, YOU HAVE SOFTWARE
COMPANIES THAT ACT AS THE AI
LAYER FOR CORPORATIONS GOING
FORWARD.
IS THAT A FAIR ARGUMENT?
IS THAT THE FUTURE WE ARE
LOOKING AT FOR SOFTWARE?
>> THIS HAS BEEN ONE OF OUR
BIGGER REASONS FOR SAYING THE
BIG ENTERPRISE SOFTWARE
COMPANIES WILL BE FINE.
WE CAN EMBED THE MODELS
THEMSELVES.
THEY ARE RIGHT NOW ACCELERATING
AI INVESTMENTS TO MAKE SURE
THAT THEIR PRODUCTS ARE ALSO
INTELLIGENT.
IF THEY ARE NOT, IT IS NOT
GOING TO BE EASY FOR THEM TO
MAINTAIN THEIR MARKET SHARE,
LET ALONE SHOW GROWTH DOWN THE
ROAD. MATT:
THE 35,000 FOOT VIEW FROM ALL
OF THESE EARNINGS, ESPECIALLY
APPLE YESTERDAY, IS THAT THERE
IS HUGE DEMAND, WHETHER IT BE
FOR AI OR THE HIGHEST TECH
HIGHEST LEVEL PRODUCTS, BUT
THEY HAVE COST PRESSURES FROM
CHIPS ACROSS THE INDUSTRY, AND
THEY ARE SUPPLY CONSTRAINED
ACROSS THE INDUSTRY.
TO ME, THAT SAYS PRICES HAVE TO
RISE. IS THAT YOUR TAKE AWAY?
>> WE THINK APPLE NEEDS TO
RAISE PRICES.
AT THIS POINT, BUT THEY ARE
DOING IS NOT RAISING PRICES.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME YOU SAW
THREE CONSECUTIVE QUARTERS OF
DOUBLE-DIGIT GROWTH?
THEY HAVE GUIDED THE NEXT AS
DOUBLE DIGITS.
IT DOES NOT HAPPEN.
I THINK THEY ARE LOSING TO
CHINA BECAUSE THEY ARE NOT
RAISING PRICES AS SOME OF THEIR
COMPETITORS ARE.
IN THE CASE OF CLOUD PROVIDERS,
THEY HAVE NO CHOICE.
THE INCOMING SERVERS ARE SO
LARGE IN TERMS OF QUANTITY THAT
THEY CANNOT MANAGE IT AND THEIR
COSTS ARE GOING UP.
APPLE HAS MANAGED IT WELL, BUT
IN THE CASE OF NEW PRODUCT
LAUNCHES, WE THINK THE PRICE
INCREASE IS GOING TO COME AT
THE HIGHEST VOLUMES, WHETHER IT
IS THE PRO MAX OR THE FOLDABLE.
THAT IS WHERE YOU WILL SEE SOME
OF THE PRICE INCREASES. MATT:
WHAT ABOUT AT OPENAI OR CLAUDE,
SO WIDELY USED BY CONSUMERS.
WHAT ABOUT FOR GEMINI AND GROK?
THE CONSUMER PRICE IS $20 A
MONTH. DOES THAT HAVE TO GO UP?
THE ENTERPRISE PRICE IS 200.
DOES THAT HAVE TO GO UP?
>> AI AND ANTHROPIC DON'T NEED
TO WORRY ABOUT IT AS LONG AS
THEY GET FUNDING.
GEMINI, IT IS FREE.
THE FREE GEMINI APP RIGHT NOW
IS PHENOMENAL IN OUR VIEW.
THEY HAVE A MASSIVE SEARCH
BUSINESS TO SUBSIDIZE IT.
I DON'T THINK THAT NEEDS TO GO
UP.
THEY NEED WIDER ADOPTION RIGHT
NOW.
THEY NEED PEOPLE TO USE IT MORE
IN ORDER TO MAKE SURE THAT
EVERYBODY IS COMFORTABLE WITH
USING AI TOOLS IN THEIR DAY
WORKFLOW. DANI:
ENJOY THE REST OF YOUR FRIDAY
AND YOUR WEEKEND.
COMING UP, WALL STREET MOVES
TOWARD ELECTIONS, WITH THE
FIRST PREDICTION MARKET ETF'S.
YOU ARE WATCHING "OPEN INTEREST." ♪
MATT:
THIS IS "OPEN INTEREST." LET'S
LOOK AT THE NEW HIGHS WE ARE
REACHING IN STOCKS.
THE S&P 500, A GAIN OF HALF A
PERCENT AFTER LOCKING IN A NEW
CLOSING HIGH.
NOW THE NASDAQ DOING BETTER
THAN THE S&P.
27,600 60, THE LEVEL THERE.
IT JUST CONTINUES TO FLY HIGHER
AS CORPORATE EARNINGS AND
ESPECIALLY EARNINGS FROM TECH
POWER THIS MARKET HIGHER.
IN TERMS OF CRUDE, ACTUALLY
DOWN 1.2%, SO THAT IS GOOD
NEWS, I GUESS, FOR EQUITIES.
NOT FOR EXXON AND CHEVRON,
WHICH ARE NOW BOTH TRADING A
BUNCH.
NVIDIA TRADING UNCHANGED AS
WELL. NOT A DRAG.
APPLE UP 5%, OFFERING SOME
UPSIDE.
WE SEE AREAS RIGHT NOW DOWN
1.1% EVEN THOUGH THEY HAVE
TAKEN IN A HUGE HOLE.
MODERNA OFF 3% AS WELL.
WE ARE GOING TO HEAR FROM THE
CEO OF MODERNA.
GOING TO COME ON AND BE
INTERVIEWED BY ROMAINE AND
KATIE. LOOKING FORWARD TO THAT.
DANI: IT IS ETF FRIDAY.
PLANS FOR THE FIRST ETF'S TIED
TO POLITICAL OUTCOMES.
WE ARE JOINED BY AN ETF ANALYST
FROM BLOOMBERG INTELLIGENCE.
GREAT TO SEE YOU.
SOME OF THESE ARE COMING NEXT
WEEK. HOW DO THESE VEHICLES EVEN
WORK?
WHAT ARE THEY BETTING ON AND
BUYING AND SELLING?
>> THEY ARE FROM THREE ISSUERS.
ROUND HILL LOOKS LIKE THEY ARE
GOING TO BE THE FIRST OUT.
THEY ARE ESSENTIALLY GOING TO
BE BETS ON POLITICAL OUTCOMES.
ARE THE DEMOCRATS OR
REPUBLICANS GOING TO WIN THE
HOUSE OR THE SENATE?
AND IT IS GOING TO BE LIKE
PREDICTION MARKETS.
YOU ARE GOING TO BE ABLE TO DO
THAT THROUGH AN ETF RATHER THAN
GO TO POLYMARKET. MATT:
IT IS HARD TO UNDERSTAND HOW
THAT WORKS, ESPECIALLY IF IT
GOES TO ZERO.
HOW DOES THAT CIRCLE GET
SQUARED? JAMES:
I'M SURE THAT IS WHAT THEY HAVE
BEEN DEALING WITH, WITH THE FCC.
YOU WOULD LOSE SUBSTANTIALLY
ALL OF YOUR MONEY.
IT WON'T GO FULLY TO ZERO.
AFTER THE MIDTERM ELECTIONS IN
2026, IF REPUBLICANS WIN IT, IT
WOULD GO BASICALLY -- THE DEBT
PRICE WOULD GO TO THEORETICALLY
ZERO.
WHAT WILL HAPPEN IS THEY WILL
GO INTO TREASURIES AFTER THE
ELECTION HAPPENS.
IT IS GOING TO RESET TO THE
NEXT ELECTION.
BUILD UP LIQUIDITY.
YOU DON'T WANT TO JUST GIVE IT
UP. I THINK WHAT ALL THESE ARE
GOING TO DO IS THEY ARE GOING
TO STICK AROUND AND SIT IN
TREASURIES FOR A BIT. DANI:
A LOT OF SCRUTINY ON BETTING
MARKETS, INSIDER TRADING.
BUT IF YOU ARE DOING THIS IN AN
ETF WRAPPER, DOES THAT CHANGE
THE REGULATORY PROFILE?
ETF'S ARE MORE REGULATED THAN
PREDICTION MARKETS. JAMES:
KALSHI AND POLYMARKET ARE
FIGURING OUT WHAT INSIDER
TRADING IS.
HIGH-PROFILE CASES OF PEOPLE
GETTING CAUGHT.
I'M SURE THIS IS SOMETHING THE
FTC HAVE BEEN DISCUSSING --
WITH THE -- THE S.E.C.
HAVE BEEN DISCUSSING.
I DO NOT THINK WE WILL SEE
SPORTS BETTING COMING TO AN
ETF, BUT WE WILL SEE THE
CATEGORY GROW. DANI: WHY NOT?
WHY WOULD WE HAVE ELECTION ONCE
AND NOT SPORTS BETTING? JAMES:
BECAUSE IT IS NOT AS OFFICIAL.
THE ETF PEOPLE WILL THROW
SOMETHING AT A WALL AND PUSH
THE LIMITS.
DANI: AN INVERSE MIXED ETF?
JAMES:
YOU HAVE A CFTC CHAIRMAN THAT
IS VERY MUCH ON THE SIDE OF
PREDICTION MARKETS.
AS OF NOW, THESE THINGS ARE
FILED TO FINANCIAL MARKETS,
ECONOMICS, THINGS ALONG THOSE
LINES.
YOU COULD MAKE AN ARGUMENT THAT
WHAT IS HAPPENING IN THESE
ELECTIONS IS -- MATT:
IT IS WHAT IT IS, AS THE
PRESIDENT SAYS.
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
TUNE IN TO ETF IQ, BY THE WAY,
AND WATCH ERIC, KATIE GREIFELD,
SCARLET FU TAKE YOU THROUGH THE
ASSET CLASS, STARTING AT
MONDAY'S AT NOON.
COMING UP, MID-CAPS ARE GROWING
ATTRACTIVE.
PLUS WE TALK SURGING FUEL PRICES.
MATT:
30 MINUTES INTO THE TRADING DAY
AND SITTING AT ALL-TIME HIGHS
AGAIN ON THE S&P.
WELCOME TO BLOOMBERG "OPEN
INTEREST." DANI:
DESPITE THE FACT OIL IS STILL
AROUND A 40-YEAR HIGH, TCE IS
HIGHER, AND THE FIX IS BELOW 17.
MATT:
THE VIX IS BELOW 17 DESPITE
THOSE THINGS. DANI:
THAT'S WHAT I MEAN, YEAH. MATT:
THE JOBS NUMBER WAS UNDER
200,000. DANI:
AND EARNINGS HAVE BEEN STRONG.
ONLY 3% OF COMPANIES HAVE
REVISED EARNINGS LOWER. MATT:
A LOT OF TENSION IN THIS
MARKET, BUT I GUESS WHEN IN
DOUBT, PULL THE TRIGGER.
WE HAVE BREAKING ECONOMIC DATA
TO, -- TO ADD SOME TENSION
POTENTIALLY TO THIS MARKET.
ISM MANUFACTURING NUMBERS
CROSSING HERE.
AND IT LOOKS LIKE MANUFACTURING
IN LINE WITH WHAT WE HAD IN THE
LAST READING.
LESS THAN WHAT THE SURVEY WAS
ANTICIPATING, BUT PRICES JUST
LONG OUT OF THE WATER.
LET'S BRING IN MICHAEL MCKEE,
BLOOMBERG'S ECONOMIC AND POLICY
CORRESPONDENT.
WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THE RELEASE?
MIKE:
MAKE IT SOUND LIKE WE SHOULD BE
APPLAUDING PRICES PAID.
THEY HAD A GREAT MONTH.
PRICES PAID FOR ISM GOES UP TO
84.6.
THE HEADLINE NUMBER IS THE SAME
AS LAST MONTH.
IT COMES IN AT 52 POINT SEVEN.
THE NEW ORDERS INDEX IS UP A
LITTLE. AND EMPLOYMENT IS DOWN.
SO, THIS IS NOT AS GOOD A
REPORT AS WE HAVE GOTTEN IN
RECENT MONTHS FROM ISM, AND
CERTAINLY THE PRICES PAID
NUMBER IS GOING TO BE A WARRIOR
FOR PEOPLE, ESPECIALLY AT THE
FED, BECAUSE IT DOES SORT OF
CONFIRM WHAT THEY ALREADY KNOW.
INFLATION IS GOING UP BECAUSE
ABROAD MATERIALS PRICES BEING
STUCK, UNABLE TO GET OUT OF THE
GULF.
BACKLOG WATERS IS ALSO HIGHER.
IT ACTUALLY FALLS, AND NEW
EXPORT ORDERS ARE DOWN.
AGAIN, NOT A GREAT REPORT, AND
WE SEE IN THE COMMENTS THAT
PEOPLE SAY DEMAND FOR GOODS IS
TRENDING HIGHER THAN LAST YEAR,
BUT GEOPOLITICAL UNCERTAINTY
AND RISING OIL AND DIESEL
PRICES CONTINUE TO WEIGH ON
DEMAND.
A KIND OF SUMS UP MOST OF THE
COMMENTS I'M SEEING HERE. MATT:
THE BACKLOG FOR ORDERS IS LOWER?
MIKE:
IT IS A LITTLE BIT LOWER, MAYBE
BECAUSE THEY WERE ABLE TO CATCH
UP, IF THINGS SLOW DOWN SOME.
WE ALSO HAD SOME BREAKING FED
NEWS.
LORIE LOGAN, THE THIRD MEMBER
OF THE OPEN MARKET COMMITTEE
WHO DISSENTED ON WEDNESDAY,
BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T LIKE THE
E-ZINE BIAS IN THE FED
STATEMENT, IS OUT WITH HER
COMMENTS.
I'M INCREASINGLY CONCERNED WITH
HOW LONG IT WILL TAKE INFLATION
TO RETURN TO THE FOMC'S TARGET.
WHEN THE FOMC GIVES GUIDANCE IT
IS IMPORTANT FOR THAT ITEMS TO
REFLECT THE POLICY OUTLOOK.
IN LIGHT OF THE RISKS TO
MONETARY POLICY I BELIEVE THE
FOMC SHOULD NOT GIVE FORWARD
GUIDANCE IMPLYING A BIAS TOWARD
RATE CUTS AT THIS TIME.
NOW WE HAVE HEARD FROM ALL
THREE OF THOSE OPEN MARKET
COMMITTEE VOTERS WHO FELT THAT
WAY. MATT:
CAN I JUST ASK QUICKLY, IS THE
FED'S TARGET TO GET TO 2%?
DON'T THEY WANT TO LONG-TERM
AVERAGE 2%?
WHICH WOULD MEAN THEY NEED TO
BRING IT DOWN TO ZERO? MIKE:
THAT HAS RAISED SOME QUESTIONS
ABOUT, DO YOU HAVE TO RUN
INFLATION HOT IF IT HAS BEEN
TOO LOW FOR TOO LONG?
THERE ARE QUESTIONS ABOUT THE
TARGET AND HOW IT IS APPLIED
AND THAT IS SOMETHING KEVIN
WARSH WANTS TO LOOK AT ONCE HE
TAKES OVER. DANI:
MICHAEL, THINK YOU VERY MUCH
FOR YOUR WORK THIS MORNING.
MICHAEL MCKEE OF OUR BLOOMBERG
INTERNATIONAL ECONOMICS AND
POLICY CORRESPONDENT.
JOINING US NOW IS EMILY ROLAND
FROM MANULIFE INVESTMENT.
NOW HAVE LORIE LOGAN SAYING
NEXT MOVE COULD PLAUSIBLY BE A
RATE HIKE OR A CUT.
NEEL KASHKARI WAS SAYING THERE
MIGHT NEED TO BE A SERIES OF
HIKES IF THE STRAIT OF HORMUZ
REMAINS YES, THESE ARE
DISSENTERS AND THESE ARE NOT
THE AVERAGE, BUT YOU LOOK AT
THEM AS MAYBE A PUSH TO KEVIN
WARSH'S DESIRE TO GET CUTS.
AND THEN MAYBE THAT ALSO MEANS
YOUR INVESTMENT THESIS FOR THE
YEAR NEEDS TO SOMEWHAT ALTER.
IF WE ARE NOT GOING TO GET
NECESSARILY THE CUTS THIS
MARKET IS PRICING IN.
EMILY: GOOD MORNING.
WE THINK IT IS THE RIGHT THING
FOR THE FED TO BE DOING RIGHT
NOW, IS TO BE COMING OUT WITH
THIS MORE HAWKISH LANGUAGE.
IT IS SO THEY CAN BE DOVISH
LATER.
IF YOU THINK ABOUT WHAT IS
GOING ON RIGHT NOW, IT IS NOT
JUST ABOUT HIGHER OIL PRICES.
THE U.S.
ECONOMY IS GOING TO A SUGAR
RUSH TODAY AND THERE IS OTHER
FACTORS AT PLAY.
YOU HAVE TAX REFUNDS WHICH ARE
ELEVATED VERSUS PRIOR YEARS.
YOU NOW HAVE TARIFF REFUNDS IN
THE MIX.
YOU HAVE INCREASED CAPEX
SPENDING IN THE WAKE OF THE ONE
BIG, BEAUTIFUL BILL.
THERE IS AN INFLATIONARY
IMPULSE AT PLAY HERE OVER THE
SHORT TERM.
ONCE WE CAN GET THROUGH THIS
SUGAR RUSH AND THE STIMULUS
WEARS OFF OUR VIEW IS THAT THE
MORE STRUCTURAL FORCES CAUSING
A DECELERATION IN ECONOMIC
GROWTH, THINGS AROUND THE LABOR
MARKET DETERIORATING, WAGE
GROWTH SHOULD -- GROWTH
SLOWING, WE THINK ALL OF THOSE
TRENDS RESUME AND THE FED CAN
HAVE SOME COVER TO CUT.
BUT FOR NOW IT IS UNCLEAR AND
THERE IS NOT A LOT TO BE DOVISH
ABOUT IN THIS MARKET OR THE
ECONOMY. MATT:
IF THERE ARE INFLATIONARY
IMPULSES FROM THE BIGGER TAX
REFUNDS, FROM THE NEW TAX RULES
IN THE BIG BEAUTIFUL BILL, AND
OBVIOUSLY THE CLOSURE OF THE
STRAIT OF HORMUZ, AT WHAT POINT
DOES THAT START AFFECTING
EARNINGS ESTIMATES?
BECAUSE YOU DON'T REALLY SEE IT.
THEY JUST CONTINUE TO MOVE
HIGHER AND HIGHER. EMILY:
EARNINGS ARE TOTALLY IMPERVIOUS
TO ANY OF THESE ISSUES, AS OUR
STOCK PRICES.
YOU ARE SEEING IT ON THE FIXED
INCOME SIDE.
OBVIOUSLY RATES HAVE BACKED UP.
SO, PRETTY CONTAINED HERE, BUT
YOU HAVE SEEN A PRIMARY
MECHANISM, NO, SEEING IT ON THE
FIXED INCOME SIDE.
EARNINGS ARE ABSOLUTELY BOOMING.
MATT: AND CLIMBING, RIGHT?
EARNINGS ESTIMATES ARE NOW 20%.
EMILY: 20%.
YOU LOOK AT THE 21 TIMES
FORWARD P/E RATIO, FRANKLY THAT
HAS BEEN FLATTERED BY THE FACT
THAT EARNINGS ESTIMATES ARE
JUST SO ELEVATED.
IT IS A GLOBAL PHENOMENON.
WE LOOK SPECIFICALLY AT MOBILE
SEMI CONDUCTOR STOCKS, EVERY
COMPANY AROUND THE WORLD IS
JUST RIDING THE WAVE OF
EARNINGS REVISIONS WE HAVE SEEN
IN SEMI CONDUCTORS.
IT IS ALMOST PARABOLIC.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE ALL COUNTRY
WORLD INDEX, SEMI CONDUCTOR
INDEX, EARNINGS ESTIMATES HAVE
GONE UP 1000% OVER THE LAST 10
YEARS.
A LOT OF THAT HAS ACTUALLY COME
OVER THE LAST 12 MONTHS.
I THINK IT IS IMPORTANT TO
POINT OUT THAT DYNAMIC AS IT
RELATES TO THE IMPORTANCE OF
THIS VERY SMALL HANDFUL OF
NAMES. DANI:
DOESN'T THE MARKET REFLECT THAT?
THE PHILLY SEMICONDUCTOR INDEX
HAD AN INSANELY GOOD APRIL.
IT'S BEST MONTH SINCE FEBRUARY
2000, THE MONTH BEFORE THE DOT
COM BUBBLE BURST. [LAUGHTER]
EMILY: WE DON'T WANT TO RUSH THE
COMPARISONS ON THAT.
YOU ARE RIGHT.
I LOOK AT MARKETS LIKE SOUTH
KOREA, A LOOK AT JAPAN.
THE SOUTH KOREAN STOCK MARKET
IS UP 16% YEAR TODAY.
TIME ONE IS UPPERMOST 40%.
AGAIN, THIS IS DOWN TO A
HANDFUL OF SMALL NAMES.
THE GOOD NEWS IS THE EARNINGS
ARE THERE.
THE EARNINGS RESULTS ARE COMING
IN VERY POSITIVE.
THE FUNDAMENTAL CASE IS THEY,
WHICH I THINK YOU COULD ARGUE
IS DIFFERENT THEN WHAT HAPPENED
IN THE LATE 19 90'S.
BUT WE NEED TO BE AWARE WHEN
THERE IS SO MUCH MOMENTUM, SO
MUCH TECHNICALS REALLY
SUPPORTING THESE MOVES
TYPICALLY WHEN THINGS GO UP IN
PARABOLIC FASHION THEY CANNOT
STAY THERE FOREVER.
I THINK A MORE DIVERSIFIED
APPROACH, LOOKING FOR HIGHER
QUALITY STOCKS IN THESE PARTS
OF THE MARKET MAKES MORE SENSE.
MATT:
AT THE SAME TIME I THINK IT WAS
NICK COLE'S WHO WAS WRITING A
COUPLE OF DAYS AGO ABOUT FUND
FLOWS IN THE U.S.
UP FOR A FIFTH CONSECUTIVE WEEK.
YOU IN YOUR NOTES TALK ABOUT
MARKET TECHNICALS AND SYSTEMIC
TRENDS THAT HAVE GONE FROM
BEING BEARISH TO BULLISH.
I MEAN, AT THE SAME TIME AS
EARNINGS ESTIMATES CONTINUE TO
BOGGLE OUR MINDS AND CLIMB
QUARTER AFTER QUARTER, ALL THE
POSITIONING, ALL OF THE
SENTIMENT, EVERYTHING IS ON THE
UPSIDE. EMILY: YEAH.
IT IS AMAZING.
WE TIME YOU TURN ON BLOOMBERG
THERE IS ANOTHER STRATEGIST.
EVEN SOME THAT HAVE BEEN
BEARISH COMING ON THE SHOWS AND
TALKING ABOUT SHIFTING THEIR
VIEWS.
OF COURSE WE TALKED A LOT ABOUT
THE EARNINGS SUPPORT THERE.
THE ECONOMY IS HOLDING IN HERE
PRETTY WELL TOO.
INITIAL CLAIMS AT 189,000 THIS
WEEK? THAT IS AWESOME.
SOME OF THE PMI DATA COMING IN
HAVE BEEN SUPPORTIVE.
YOU SAW EARLIER IN THE WEEK THE
MARKET VERSION OF PMI'S SHOWING
SOME STRENGTH. THE U.S.
ECONOMY IS HOLDING IN REALLY
WELL HERE.
EARNINGS GROWTH IS STRONG.
AGAIN, I THINK THERE IS A LOT
OF POTENTIALLY OVERLY-BULLISH
SENTIMENT WE WANT TO BE CAREFUL
ABOUT, BUT THERE IS ALSO A LOT
TO LIKE.
WE CAME INTO THIS WEEK HOPING
THE MARKETS WOULD BE ABLE TO
FOCUS ON FUNDAMENTALS, FOCUS ON
EARNINGS INSTEAD OF JUST THE
GEOPOLITICAL HEADLINES.
THAT HAPPENED, AND AGAIN WE SAW
THAT SUPPORT FROM A FUNDAMENTAL
STANDPOINT. DANI:
JUST GETTING BACK TO THE
TECHNICALS MATT WAS
REFERENCING, YOU HAVE TAX
REFUNDS, SO RETAIL INVESTORS
ARE GOING TO BE BUYING,
INSTITUTIONS ARE DIPPING INTO
THE MARKET AFTER THE GROSSING,
AND THEN YOU HAVE THIS HUGE
WALL OF BUYBACKS.
STOCK BUYBACKS SET TO HIT
SOMETHING LIKE $1 TRILLION.
IPO ISSUANCES ARE ONLY $200
BILLION. THOSE ARE NOT JUST A
SUPPLY-DEMAND IMBALANCE.
THAT IS ALSO CONTINUING TO PUSH
STOCKS HIGHER.
EMILY: THAT IS A GREAT POINT.
WE ARE LIVING IN A WORLD OF
STOCKMARKET NIRVANA RIGHT NOW
AND NOT ONLY ARE THE
FUNDAMENTALS THERE, BUT YOU'VE
ALSO GOT THESE TECHNICAL MOVES
DRIVING MARKETS HIGHER.
THERE IS AN OLD PHRASE, DON'T
CONFUSE BRAINS WITH A BULL
MARKET.
YOU WANT TO BE MINDFUL OF THAT.
MARKETS ARE MOVING HIGHER.
YOU HAVE TO RESPECT THE TREND.
I THINK PARTICIPATING, BUT
PEELING OFF A LITTLE BIT OF
RISK HERE, YOU THINK ABOUT THE
AREAS, SMALL CAPS,
EMERGING-MARKET EQUITIES,
JAPAN, THEY ARE MORE CYCLICAL,
THEY ARE MORE EXPOSED TO HIGHER
OIL PRICES AND GEOPOLITICAL
CONFLICTS.
EUROPE, JAPAN, MAJOR OIL
IMPORTERS, THEY HAVE NOT BEEN
TOUCHED.
WE THINK ABOUT LEANING INTO
HIGHER QUALITY PARTS OF THE
MARKET, LOOKING AT MID-CAP
STOCKS, FOCUSING ON EQUITIES
THAT ARE MORE DEFENSIVE.
THEY HAVE EXPOSURE TO AREAS
LIKE INDUSTRIALS, UTILITIES.
SOMETHING TO COMPLEMENT THAT
SEMICONDUCTOR EXPOSURE THAT CAN
HELP MOVE FORWARD WITH THE
DIVERSIFIED PORTFOLIO. MATT:
GREAT TO GET SOME TIME WITH YOU.
EMILY ROLAND OF MANULIFE JOHN
HANCOCK TALKING TO US AS WE IT
ANOTHER ALL-TIME HIGH.
LET'S GET A LOOK AT WHAT IS
GOING ON IN TERMS OF THE SINGLE
STOCK STORIES THAT WE HAVE AT
THIS HOUR.
CHEVRON AND EXXON ARE A COUPLE
THAT BEAT EARNINGS ESTIMATES
DUE TO HIGHER OIL PRICES FUELED
BY THE WAR IN IRAN.
THEY ARE ALSO PRODUCING MORE IN
THE PERMIAN AND THE SHARES ARE
DOWN, BUT THEY HAVE BEEN ON A
TEAR. THIS LOOKS LIKE SOME
PROFIT-TAKING FOR OIL. DANI:
THEN THERE WAS SAND DESK.
IT DELIVERED
BETTER-THAN-EXPECTED RESULTS.
ANALYST SAID IT WAS NOT ENOUGH
TO MEET -- I MEAN THEY SAY IT
WAS NOT ENOUGH, BUT SHARES ARE
UP 3.75 PERCENT.
I THINK THEY MET THE BAR AND
EXCEEDED IT. MATT:
APPLE, POSTING DOUBLE-DIGIT
SALES GROWTH AND DELIVERING A
BETTER-THAN-EXPECTED REVENUE
FORECAST EVEN AS THE CEO WARNS
OF HIGHER CHIP COSTS.
NO ONE CARES ABOUT INFLATION
TODAY. APPLE UP 5.5%. DANI:
WE ARE GOING TO TALK MORE ON
THAT ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE
BREAK.
YOU'RE GOING TO SPEAK WITH
APPLE ANALYST WILL POWER ON
BLOOMBERG "OPEN INTEREST." ♪
MATT:
LET'S GET OUT OF HIGH INTEREST
AND LOOKING WHAT IS MAKING
HEADLINES AROUND THE WORLD.
SKULPTOR CAPITAL MANAGEMENT IS
-- PUTTING LEAVEN ALONGSIDE
OTHER SENIOR LEADERS TO SHARE
INVESTMENT CONTROL.
THE FIRM CALLS IN A MODERNIZED
STRUCTURE AIMED AT CONTINUITY
AFTER YEARS OF LEADERSHIP DRAMA.
WHILE LEVIN HAS NOT CONFIRMED
PLANS INSIDERS SAY HE COULD
EXIT BY EARLY NEXT YEAR.
THE PENTAGON IS EXPANDING ITS
AI CAPABILITIES CITING DEALS
WITH NVIDIA AND MICROSOFT AND
AMAZON.
THE MOVE FOLLOWS ALL OUT WITH
ANTHROPIC OVER LIMITS ON
MILITARY USE.
OFFICIALS SAY THE BULLS AND AI
FIRST MILITARY FORCE, EXPANDING
ACCESS TO TOOLS INCLUDING FOR
AUTONOMOUS WEAPONS DEVELOPMENT
WHILE INSISTING HUMANS MAKE
FINAL DECISIONS.
APPLE BEATS EXPECTATIONS WITH
THE BOLD FORECAST WITH SALES UP
BUDGETS MUCH AS 17% IN THE NEXT
QUARTER.
THE STRENGTH IS DRIVEN BY
STRONG IPHONE DEMAND AND NEW
PRODUCTS LIKE LOW-COST MACBOOK
NEOS.
MACBOOK SHORTAGES COULD LAST
MONTH AND RISING MEMORY COSTS
HITS MARGINS.
MEANWHILE THE RISING CEO JOHN
TURNES WILL FACE CHALLENGES IN
ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE. DANI:
WILLPOWER RAISED HIS PRICE
TARGET ON THE STOCK WRITING "WE
REMAIN POSITIVE ON THE STRONG
GROWTH AND FREE CASH FLOW WITH
REVAMPED SIRI AND ADDITIONAL
CATALYSTS IN THE SECOND HALF OF
2026." WILL JOINS US NOW.
IT IS CLEAR YOU SAW THE
EARNINGS IS A POSITIVE FOR THE
COMPANY.
WHAT WERE THE STANDOUTS?
WILL: THE IPHONE CONTINUES TO
DEMONSTRATE REVITALIZATION.
JOSEPH: QUARTERS OF GROWTH.
THAT IS A BIG DRIVER BUT IT IS
NOT JUST THE IPHONE.
AS YOU JUST ALLUDED TO THE MAX
SERIES OF PRODUCTS IS
PERFORMING BETTER, WHETHER IT
IS THE MAC MINI, IT IS
BROAD-BASED SUPPORT.
THE OTHER KEY IS THEY ARE
SEEING STRONG TRACTION INTO THE
JUNE QUARTER. MATT:
DON'T THEY HAVE TO BE CAREFUL
NOT TO REST ON THEIR IPHONE
MACBOOK LAURELS?
AS WE KNOW FROM THE HISTORY OF
COMPANIES LIKE NOKIA, THINGS
CAN CHANGE AT THE DROP OF A HAT.
I AM NOT SUGGESTING THAT
HAPPENS ANY TIME SOON BUT NO
ONE KNOWS IF OR WHEN IT WILL.
SHOULDN'T THEY BE PUTTING OUT
NEW PRODUCTS, DIFFERENT LINES?
WILL:
I HAVE THE GRAVEYARD OF
APPLE'S COMPETITORS BEHIND ME
AS YOU LOOK AT THE DEVICE
PORTFOLIOS.
IT IS ALWAYS A BIG QUESTION.
WE WILL HAVE THE NEXT BEST
WIDGET.
AS ALL OF US KNOW PART OF THE
STRENGTH OF APPLE HAS BEEN THE
ECOSYSTEM.
WHETHER IT IS WATCHES, AIRPODS,
IPADS.
WITHOUT QUESTION YOU HAVE TO
CONTINUE TO EXPAND THAT.
THEY ARE LOOKING AT
OPPORTUNITIES IN THE HOME.
AI WILL PRESUMABLY BE A BIG
PART OF THAT.
TO SOLIDIFY THE ECOSYSTEM
BENEFITS THAT THEY HAVE HAD NOW
OVER THE LAST DECADE PLUS. DANI:
ALL OF THIS AND STRONG DEMAND
DESPITE THE FACT THAT SIRI
STILL SUCKS. IT IS MISERABLE.
IT DOES NOT DO WHAT IT SHOULD
DO .
I OPENED CHATGPT AND TALK TO
THAT THERE.
WHEN WILL THEY GET SOMETHING
THAT COULD BE POWERED BY
WHATEVER AI AGENT I DECIDE TO
USE AND HOW BIG OF AN UPLIFT
WILL THAT BE?
THERE IS STILL DEMAND EVEN
THOUGH THAT ELEMENT IS NOT
PRESENT IN THEIR PRODUCTS? WILL:
THE GOOD NEWS FOR APPLE'S THEY
ARE ENTERING INTO THE AI
OPPORTUNITY LATER THAN WE AND
OTHERS HAD HOPED.
WE HAD HOPED THEY MIGHT BE
FURTHER ALONG ON THIS JOURNEY.
THE REST OF THE PORTFOLIO IS
SURGING RIGHT NOW.
ENTERING INTO AI IN MORE OF A
POSITION OF STRENGTH THAN SOME
MIGHT HAVE THOUGHT.
AT THIS POINT IT IS MORE THE
ON-SITE OPTIONALITY.
ALL EYES WILL BE ON WWDC.
ONE OF THE TEA LEAVES WE CAN
PICK UP THERE WITH RESPECT TO
WHAT THEY ARE DOING INTERNALLY
AND WHAT THEY ARE TRYING TO
DEVELOP WITH GEMINI.
I THINK TAKING A STEP BACK AND
RELYING ON OUTSIDE PARTNERS
MAKES A LOT OF SENSE.
YOU LOOK AT THE BENEFITS THEY
HAVE ACCRUED FROM THE
RELATIONSHIP WITH GOOGLE IN THE
PAST. THE OPPORTUNITY TO EXPAND
THAT IN THE AI REALM WITH A
PLATFORM LIKE GEMINI IS ONE OF
THE STANDOUT PLAYERS IN THAT
SPACE MAKES A LOT OF SENSE.
MATT:
DANI AND I JUST GOT FROM MIAMI
WHERE WE WERE BEATING THE DRUM
TO THE FORMULA ONE RACE COMING
UP THIS WEEKEND.
IT STRIKES ME THAT NO ONE GIVES
APPLE CREDIT FOR THE AMAZINGLY
LOW PRICE THEY PAID FOR F1
CONSIDERING HOW BIG IT IS AND
HOW MUCH GROWTH THEY COULD SEE.
I KNOW IT IS A VERY SMALL PART
OF A $4 TRILLION COMPANY WHEN
YOU LOOK AT IT LIKE THAT.
DON'T YOU THINK THERE IS SO
MUCH OPPORTUNITY FOR APPLE TV,
ESPECIALLY WITH LIVE SPORTS?
WILL: THERE IS MORE OPPORTUNITY.
THEY HAVE DIPPED THEIR TOES IN
THE WATER WITH BASEBALL, PARTS
OF SOCCER.
NOW I HAVE ONE -- NOW F0-1 IS A
GLOBAL PHENOMENON.
I THINK THAT DOES GET
UNDERAPPRECIATED AND GETS
FOLDED INTO THE SERVICES
BUSINESS WHICH IS PART OF THE
SECRET SAUCE FOR APPLE.
THAT IS NOW A $100 BILLION PLUS
SEGMENT FOR THEM.
THEY ARE SEEING SOME
ACCELERATION.
ASIDE FROM TV, MORE APPLICATION
DEVELOPMENT GENERALLY FOR AI
AND GENERALLY OF AI
CAPABILITIES AND TOOLS TO HELP
BENEFIT THAT BUSINESS.
WITHOUT QUESTION TV IS A KEY
OPPORTUNITY FOR THEM AND IT
HELPS IN OUR JUDGMENT SOLIDIFY
THE ECOSYSTEM. DANI:
IT IS A BIG PICTURE QUESTION I
HAVE THE RIGHT APPLE USED TO BE
KNOWN AS A COMPANY THAT DID NOT
GIVE CONSUMERS WHAT THEY
WANTED, THEY TOLD CONSUMERS
WHAT THEY WANTED.
IT FEELS LIKE THE PRODUCT
ROLLOUT IS DIFFERENT NOW.
WE WILL GET A FOLDING IPHONE.
THEY TRIED WITH A VR HEADSET TO
RATE WITH THE NEW CEO COMING
FROM A HARDWARE BACKGROUND DOES
APPLE GET BACK TO THAT EAT
THOSE? WILL:
THAT IS A GREAT QUESTION.
THE FOLDABLE WORLD IS ONE
EXAMPLE.
APPLE HAS NOT NECESSARILY BEEN
THE FIRST TO MARKET.
SOME CALLED THE NORTH STAR, THE
POINT IS ABOUT HAVING THE BEST
PRODUCTS.
THEY HAVE TAKEN MORE TIME TO
ROLL OUT THEIR PHONE.
I THINK THAT IS STILL IN
UNDERESTIMATED OPPORTUNITY FOR
THEM.
I AM CAUTIOUSLY OPTIMISTIC THAT
COULD BE AN UPSIDE SURPRISE IN
TERMS OF CUSTOMER DEMAND AND
DEMONSTRATING THE INNOVATION
ENGINE IS STILL ALIVE TO DRIVE
CUSTOMER TRAFFIC TO THEIR
STORES.
IT IS ALSO AN ASP LEFT TO THE
DEGREE YOU CAN CHARGE MORE FOR
SOME OF THESE HIGHER END
PRODUCTS, THAT IS BENEFICIAL
TOO.
IT IS ON THE NEW CEO SHOULDERS
AND THEY CAN BRING THAT
HARDWARE INNOVATION BACK TO
BEAR. MATT:
THANKS FOR JOINING US.
WILLPOWER OF BAIRD.
COMING UP BRUNSWICK CEO DAVE
FOULKES JOINS US TO TALK ABOUT
BOATS AS WE ENTER THE SUMMER
WITH HIGHER GAS PRICES. ♪
MATT: LET'S GET A CHECK ON THE
MARKETS. IT IS FRIDAY.
THANK GOD.
S&P 500 UP .8% TO 7268.
MASTEC GETTING MORE THAN 1%.
THIS IS EUPHORIA -- NASDAQ
GAINING MORE THAN 1%.
ACTUALLY IT IS COMING BACK DOWN
NOW.
BRENT COMING DOWN TO A $107.
COMING UP, BRUNSWICK BEATS AND
RAISES ITS OUTLOOK.
MATT:
BRUNSWICK REPORTING EARNINGS
YESTERDAY, AND THE SHARES ARE
HIGHER BECAUSE THE BOAT MAKER
BEAT EXPECTATIONS AND RAISED
ITS OUTLOOK.
BUT HIGHER FUEL COSTS ARE
STARTING TO HIT BOATERS.
WE WANT TO ASK MORE ABOUT THIS
TENSION.
WHO BETTER TO ASK THAN THE CEO?
DAVE FOULKES JOINS US.
PRETTY EXCITING AS WE GET INTO
BETTER WEATHER, AT LEAST FOR US
IN THE NORTHEAST, TO THINK MORE
ABOUT BOATING, AND OBVIOUSLY
THAT SHOWS THROUGH IN YOUR
EARNINGS AND YOUR OUTLOOK.
AT THE SAME TIME, THESE THINGS
ARE GAS GUZZLERS TO SOME EXTENT.
SO HOW DOES THAT AFFECT THE
DEMAND? DAVE:
GREAT TO BE WITH YOU, MATT,
THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME ON.
WE HAD A GREAT QUARTER, AS YOU
SAID EARLIER, BEAT TOP AND
BOTTOM LINES.
GAS PRICES ARE TALKING POINT AT
THE MOMENT, BUT THEY ARE STILL
REALLY WITHIN HISTORICAL BOUNDS.
YOU KNOW, WE DON'T MAKE MEGA
YACHTS.
WE MAKE BOATS IN THE 20-40-FEET
RANGE.
WHAT'S NOT WELL UNDERSTOOD IS
THOSE BOATS USE IN A YEAR ABOUT
25% OF THE FUEL OF AN AVERAGE
PASSENGER VEHICLE.
THE FUEL IS A RELATIVELY SMALL
COMPONENT OF THE RUNNING
CUSTOMER BOAT.
FOR A LOT OF BOATS IT IS LESS
THAN 10%.
ALTHOUGH IT IS A TALKING POINT,
IT IS NOT DETERRING NEW BOAT
SALES OR PARTICIPATION AT THE
MOMENT. DANI:
AND I KNOW IN THE MARKETS WHERE
THERE IS REALLY DIRECT
EXPOSURE, BE IT THE MIDDLE EAST
OR ASIA, WHERE OIL SUPPLIES ARE
TIGHTER, AGAIN, IT IS SMALL IN
TERMS OF YOUR OVERALL BUSINESS,
BUT WHAT ARE YOU SEEING IN
THOSE MARKETS?
HOW ARE CLIENTS IN THE MIDDLE
EAST AND ASIA BEHAVING? DAVE:
AS YOU SAID, WE ARE A $5.5
MILLION COMPANY.
OUR EXPOSURE IN THE MIDDLE EAST
IS LESS THAN $100 MILLION.
IT IS A SMALL PORTION OF OUR
REVENUE, BUT A GOOD MARKET FOR
US. AND SOMEWHAT SURPRISINGLY,
DEMAND IS STILL GOOD.
ACTUALLY GETTING THE BOATS
THERE, THE LOGISTICS, BOATS,
AND ENGINES IS MORE TROUBLESOME
AT THE MOMENT, BUT DEMAND IS
STILL GOOD.
WE EXPECT A MODEST IMPACT ON
REVENUE FROM THE REGION, NOT
VERY SUBSTANTIAL AT THE MOMENT.
MATT:
WE WERE JUST DOWN IN MIAMI, AND
I IMAGINE THAT MUST BE ONE OF
YOUR HOTTEST MARKETS FOR A
C-RAY, ESPECIALLY.
YOU HAVE BRANDS I GREW UP WITH
LIKE BOSTON WHALER, MERCURY IS
PRETTY MUCH SYNONYMOUS WITH
BOAT ENGINES.
WHAT ARE THE HOTTEST MARKETS
FOR YOU AROUND THE U.S.
RIGHT NOW?
WHERE DO YOU SEE THE MOST
GROWTH? DAVE:
YOU'RE RIGHT, MIAMI -- FLORIDA
IS A STRONG MARKET FOR US,
PARTICULARLY FOR OUR PREMIUM
PRODUCT LINES.
BOSTON WHALER, MERCURY.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE MIAMI BOAT
SHOW RECENTLY, MERCURY HAD 60%
OF ALL THE OUTPUTS THERE.
SALES OF MERCURY AND BOSTON
WHALER WERE UP.
IF YOU LOOK AT THE PALM BEACH
SHOW, WHICH WAS JUST A FEW
MONTHS AGO, WE HAD REALLY
STRONG SHARE AGAIN AND REVENUE
UP 40% YEAR-OVER-YEAR.
THOSE PREMIUM MARKETS ARE
REALLY STRONG FOR OUR PREMIUM
PRODUCTS. MATT:
HAVE YOU SEEN A PICKUP THERE,
DAVE?
AS WALL STREET MOVES SOUTH AND
THE GUYS FROM CITADEL GET THEIR
BONUSES AND THINK, WHY DON'T I
HAVE A SKI BOAT, HAVE YOU SEEN
REAL GROWTH DOWN THERE? DAVE:
IT CONTINUES TO BE A VERY
STRONG MARKET.
HE SAID IN THE FIRST QUARTER
THAT UNIT SALES WERE ABOUT FLAT
YEAR-OVER-YEAR, BUT BENEATH
THAT YOU SEE PREMIUM MUCH
STRONGER THAN VALUE.
AND OF COURSE FLORIDA IS MAINLY
A PREMIUM SALTWATER MARKET.
I DON'T KNOW IF WE CAN DIRECTLY
CORRELATE THOSE SPECIFIC MOVES
OF INDIVIDUALS OUT OF NEW YORK
TO FLORIDA, BUT I WOULD SAY
FLORIDA CONTINUES TO BE VERY
STRONG -- MATT:
I'M TRYING TO BUILD A NARRATIVE
HERE, DAVE. DANI:
CAMPAIGN FOR YOURSELF TO BE IN
MIAMI FOR ONE OF THESE BOATS.
MATT:
THE WHOLE INDUSTRY MOVING DOWN
THERE, THIS IS REAL MONEY IF
YOU HAVE A FREE SATURDAY OR
SUNDAY, WHICH MANY, TO BE FAIR,
DON'T, YOU WANT TO BE ON THE
WATER. DANI:
AND THE WEATHER IS ALWAYS NICE.
I'M INTERESTED IN THE
DIFFERENCE BETWEEN PREMIUM AND
VALUE.
WHAT IS VALUE LAGGING BEHIND?
DAVE:
I THINK IT IS A LITTLE BIT OF
THE K-SHAPED ECONOMY
PHENOMENON, DANI WHAT WE DO SEE
IS YOU CAN EVEN SPLIT VALUE OFF
A BIT.
VALUE ALUMINUM BOATS, FISHING
BOAT SAN ARE PRETTY -- FISHING
BOATS ARE PRETTY STRONG.
WHERE WE SEE A BIT MORE
WEAKNESS IS IN THE VALUE
FIBERGLASS BOAT.
THAT IS PROBABLY A LITTLE BIT
MORE CAUTIOUS OF THE MOMENT DUE
TO ECONOMIC SITUATION.
BUT FOR THOSE KIND OF BOATS, AS
YOU KNOW, WE HAVE FREEDOM BOAT
CLUB, A MODEL THAT ALLOWS
PEOPLE TO GET ON THE WATER
WITHOUT PURCHASING BOAT A
THROUGH A SUBSCRIPTION MODEL.
WE ARE TRYING TO GET AS MANY
PEOPLE INTO BOATING FROM ACROSS
THE DEMOGRAPHIC SPECTRUM AS
POSSIBLE IN A WAY THAT SUITS
THEM. MATT:
I ONLY USE THOSE RUNABOUTS IN A
DUCK SEASON BECAUSE I NEED TO
GET OUT ON THE SOUND TISSUE
THOSE BIRDS.
--TO SHOOT THOSE BIRDS.
I'M WONDERING ABOUT THE
INFRASTRUCTURE QUESTION.
AFTER BEING IN MIAMI AND
TALKING WITH ALL THESE
PROFESSIONALS MOVING DOWN
THERE, THEY NEEDED NOT JUST
NICE WEATHER AND A PLACE TO
LIVE, BUT HOMES TO BUY, SCHOOLS
WHETHER KIDS CAN GO.
AND FOR YOUR BUSINESS, THEY
NEED OBVIOUSLY TO HAVE A DOCK.
THEY NEED TO HAVE A MARINA TO
SOME EXTENT.
HOW IMPORTANT IS THAT TO YOU,
AND WHAT KIND OF MARINA GROWTH
DO YOU SEE IN THIS COUNTRY?
DAVE:
INTEREST IN MARINAS IS VERY
STRONG AT THE MOMENT.
THERE ARE A NUMBER OF INVESTORS
BUYING MARINAS AND EXPANDING
MARINAS. FOR THE U.S.
OVERALL HAS A WEALTH OF MARINA
INFRASTRUCTURE.
THERE ARE ABOUT 10,000 MARINAS
IN THE U.S.
IT IS VERY WELL SERVED.
SO SOMETIMES AN INDIVIDUAL
MIGHT STRUGGLE TO GET INTO
PARTICULAR MARINA.
THERE IS A LOT OF INVESTMENT
GOING IN WHICH IS VERY
SUPPORTIVE FOR OUR BUSINESS,
VERY SUPPORTIVE FOR BOAT SALES
BUT ALSO FREEDOM BOAT CLUB
BECAUSE WE RENTED THOSE MARINA
SLIPS FOR OUR PURPOSES. DANI:
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US, DAVE
FOULKES, BRUNSWICK CEO.
WE ARE JUST OVER AN HOUR INTO
THE TRADING DAY.
TRADING AT ALL-TIME HIGHS AFTER
HUGE MONTH. UP .6%.
NASDAQ UP .7%.
SOFTWARE IS HAVING A GOOD DAY.
APPLE HAD A SOLID SET OF
RESULTS.
10-YEAR LITTLE CHANGED, WHILE
BRENT CRUDE DIPS BELOW 109.
IT IS DOWN 2% THIS MORNING.
COMING UP ON THE SHOW, MIAMI IS
BOOMING LIKE NEVER BEFORE, AS
MATT JUST EXPLAINED.
REAL ESTATE BILLIONAIRE
EXPLAINS WHITE MONEY AND TALENT
AND POWER ARE MOVING SOUTH.
THIS IS BLOOMBERG. ♪
JORGE PÉREZ, THE BILLIONAIRE
FOUNDER OF RELATED GROUP AND A
DEFINING FORCE BEHIND MIAMI'S
REAL-ESTATE BOOM, AS WELL AS
PHILANTHROPY AND ART SCENE, SAT
DOWN WITH ME AT THE BLOOMBERG
HOUSE MIAMI FOR A WIDE-RANGING
CONVERSATION.
HE DISCUSSED THE POLICY AND
BUSINESS DYNAMICS DRIVING
MIAMI'S EMERGENCE AS A GLOBAL
HUB. JORGE:
THE BIGGEST BOOM I'VE EVER SEEN.
BEFORE WHEN WE WERE SELLING
CONDOMINIUMS OR RENTING
APARTMENTS, WE HAD A HUGE
AMOUNT OF TRAFFIC FROM LATIN
AMERICA.
AND WHAT WE HAVE SEEN RECENTLY
IS THAT HAS CHANGED TO HAVE A
HUGE AMOUNT OF TRAFFIC FROM NEW
YORK, CALIFORNIA, NORTHEASTERN
AND NORTHWESTERN CITIES THAT
HAVE HAD PROBLEMS, POLITICAL
PROBLEMS, TAXATION PROBLEMS,
HOMELESSNESS PROBLEMS. AND THEY
ARE COMING TO MIAMI.
OVER 50% OF OUR BUYERS IN THE
CONDOMINIUMS ARE PEOPLE COMING
HERE TO STAY.
COMPANIES LIKE CITADEL, YOU
KNOW, IS BRINGING A LOT OF
PEOPLE IN.
KEN GRIFFIN IS A FANTASTIC GUY,
DONE FANTASTIC THINGS FOR MIAMI.
A LOT OF COMPANIES ARE
FOLLOWING . MATT:
HOW IMPORTANT HAVE DEMOCRATIC
POLITICIANS BEEN FOR GROWTH?
GAVIN NEWSOM, KATHY HOCHUL,
ZOHRAN MAMDANI, ARE THEY REALLY
SENDING SO MANY WEALTHY PEOPLE
DOWN HERE FROM CALIFORNIA AND
NEW YORK? JORGE:
THOSE THREE WE HAVE NAMED BEST
REALTORS OF THE YEAR FOR MIAMI.
YES, YES, YOU KNOW, THERE IS A
SENTIMENT IN MANY BUSINESSES
THAT THEY ARE FED UP WITH THE
ANTI-RICH, ANTIBUSINESS
POLITICS.
TAXATION, AS YOU KNOW, IN MANY
AREAS HAS INCREASED
DRAMATICALLY TO PAY FOR THOSE
SERVICES. MATT:
WHAT DO YOU THINK THE
POLITICIANS HERE HAVE DONE
RIGHT?
-TALKING TO BUSINESS LEADERS
WHO SAID JEB BUSH DID A GREAT
JOB SETTING UP MIAMI FOR
SUCCESS.
I HAVE BEEN TALKING TO BUSINESS
LEADERS WHO SAID RON DESANTIS
HAS BEEN A SUCCESS AS GOVERNOR
FOR THIS CITY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK THEY HAVE
DONE RIGHT? JORGE:
YOU MENTIONED TO REPUBLICANS
WHICH HAVE DONE A LOT FOR
FLORIDA, BUT SO LOCALLY THE
DEMOCRATIC, THE CITY AND COUNTY
MAYOR ARE DEMOCRATS. MATT:
AND YOU ARE A DEMOCRAT. JORGE:
AND BUSINESSMAN.
I'M A CAPITALIST. I THINK OF
MYSELF AS A CAPITALIST LOOK
BLOOMBERG IS, CAPITALIST WITH A
CONSCIENCE.
WE BELIEVE WE NEED TO ELEVATE
EVERYBODY SO EVERYBODY
PARTICIPATES IN THE FRUITS OF
BUSINESS.
I THINK WHAT THEY HAVE DONE IS
THEY'VE MADE IT BUSINESS
FRIENDLY.
WHEN YOU GO GET A PERMIT IN
CALIFORNIA, FOR EXAMPLE, IT CAN
TAKE YOU FOUR YEARS.
IN MIAMI IT WILL TAKE YOU SIX
MONTHS.
IT IS NOT BECAUSE THEY ARE
CUTTING ON INSPECTIONS.
IT IS BECAUSE THEY WANT TO SEE
THE CITY GROW. MATT:
WHAT ABOUT IMMIGRATION?
BECAUSE AS WE KNOW, THIS IS A
COUNTRY BUILT OFF THE LABOR OF
IMMIGRANTS, AND YOU YOURSELF
IMMIGRATED HERE AND DID VERY
WELL.
YOU ARE IN AN INDUSTRY THAT I
IMAGINE IS RELIANT ON IMMIGRANT
LABOR.
IS IT DIFFICULT TO DEVELOP
PROPERTIES?
ARE YOU HAVING TROUBLE FINDING
LABOR? JORGE:
IT'S NOT DIFFICULT TO DEVELOP
PROPERTIES YET.
BUT OUR COSTS ARE INCREASING
BECAUSE OF THAT.
YOU HAVE TO REMEMBER THAT IN
THE JOBS THAT PAY THE LEAST,
THE PEOPLE THAT ARE HANDLING
RESTAURANTS, HOTELS,
CONSTRUCTION, BEGINNING
CONSTRUCTION JOBS, MANY OF THEM
ARE IMMIGRANTS.
I THINK WE ARE GOING TO SEE
PROBLEMS IN HIRING.
WE ARE GOING TO SEE INFLATION
GROW.
AND THE TARIFFS ARE NOT MAKING
THAT PROBLEM ANY BETTER.
SO I DON'T THINK INFLATION HAS
RAMPED UP TO THE POINT THAT IT
COULD.
IF WE CONTINUE WITH A VERY
RESTRICTIVE IMMIGRATION POLICY
AND A VERY STRONG TARIFF POLICY.
SO I WOULD LIKE TO SEE THOSE
CHANGES.
I WOULD LIKE TO SEE PEOPLE THAT
HAVE WORKED IN THIS COUNTRY FOR
AN -- I DON'T KNOW IF IT IS
FIVE, 7 -- AND I HAD NO
CRIMINAL RECORD AND HAVE BEEN
PRODUCTIVE, NOT TO GET
CITIZENSHIP RIGHT AWAY, BUT YOU
HAVE A PATH TO CITIZENSHIP.
MATT:
YOU ARE CLOSE TO THE PRESIDENT.
YOU GET ALONG WITH THE
PRESIDENT. JORGE:
I USED TO GET ALONG WITH THE
PRESIDENT. WE WERE FRIENDS.
I THINK WE DID SIX TOWERS
TOGETHER AND CALL THEM TRUMP
TOWERS AND LOOKED AT DEALS IN
MEXICO, AND I LIKED DONALD VERY
MUCH.
HE WAS A GOOD FRIEND, SUPER
ENTERTAINING.
GREAT MARKETING GUY.
WHEN HE ANNOUNCED HE WAS
RUNNING FOR PRESIDENT, I WAS
VERY SURPRISED BECAUSE WE HAD
NEVER DISCUSSED POLITICS, SO I
DID NOT EVEN KNOW WHAT
POLITICAL SIDE HE WAS ON. MATT:
HE USED TO BE A DEMOCRAT. JORGE:
WHEN HE CAME UP WITH THESE
POLICIES, IT WAS VERY CONCERNED
AND I FELT THAT IF I DID NOT
SPEAK UP, I WAS SORT OF
APPROVING THOSE POLICIES.
WE HAVE GLOBAL WARMING, TARIFF
AGREEMENTS, THE WAY YOU TREAT
YOUR ALLIES.
IT HAS TO DO WITH BUILDING A
WALL, YOU KNOW?
AND HE ACTUALLY CALLED ME TO
SEE IF I WANTED TO BUILD THE
WALL, YOU KNOW?
AND I RESPONDED THAT OF COURSE
NOT. I HAD A FEW REASONS.
THE LAST OF THE REASONS IS THAT
MY NAME IS PEREZ.
WHAT SIDE OF THE WALL DO I GET
PUT IN? IN A FUNNY WAY.
AND WE TALKED ABOUT OTHER
THINGS. WE WERE VERY CLOSE.
WE GET ALONG REALLY WELL.
HE WAS EXTREMELY GENEROUS AS A
FRIEND, AND FUN, YOU KNOW?
LIKE I SAID, I THINK HE IS A
MARKETING GENIUS.
HE UNDERSTANDS WHERE THE MARKET
IS GOING.
WE DID SOME VERY SUCCESSFUL
PROJECTS.
I JUST DON'T AGREE WITH HIS
POLICIES. MATT:
GEORGE PEREZ -- JORGE PEREZ,
FOUNDER AND CHAIRMAN OF RELATED
GROUP. YOU CAN WATCH THE FULL
INTERVIEW AT BLOOMBERG.COM AND
ON THE BLOOMBERG TERMINAL.
IT WAS A GREAT CONVERSATION.
DANI: REALLY GOOD. MATT:
WE ALSO MET HIS WIFE.
THE BLOOMBERG HOUSE EVENT WAS
AMAZING.
WE DID THIS IN DAVOS'S AND IT
WAS SO SUCCESSFUL.
WE HAD BUSINESS LEADERS.
YOU SPOKE WITH SCOTT RUDIN ARE.
YOU HAVE SPORTS LEADERS.
WE TALKED TO THE PRINCIPLE FROM
AUDI, TALK TO SOMEONE FROM
FERRARI, FROM CADILLAC.
WE TALKED TO SUZY WOLF. FIFA.
YOU HAVE ALL THOSE GUESTS.
BUT THE COOLEST THING IS THE
PEOPLE, THE CLIENTS THAT COME
THERE, IT IS NOT JUST ABOUT THE
JOURNALISTIC GUESTS ON STAGE.
I MET SO MANY BLOOMBERG FANS
YESTERDAY. DANI:
IT IS THIS WONDERFUL
INTERSECTION OF FINANCE, MEDIA,
SPORTS.
MARIO CARBONE WAS THERE THE DAY
BEFORE.
HE DID A LITTLE SOCIAL VIDEO.
I BELIEVE HE SAID THAT TRUFFLE
FRIES WERE OVERRATED AND
MARTINIS ARE PERFECTLY RATED,
WHICH I WOULD DISAGREE WITH.
MATT: I HATE TRUFFLE FRIES.
DANI: REALLY? THEY ARE FUN.
MATT:
NO, FRIES ARE GOOD AS THEY ARE.
ESPRESSO MARTINIS, I TOTALLY
GET.
BUT IF YOU WANT TO GET A LITTLE
BIT PUMPED AS WELL. DANI:
WE'RE GOING TO TALK MORE ABOUT
SPORTS. AN ITALIAN FOOTBALL CLUB
LAUNCHING A NEW PLATFORM AS IT
LOOKS TO EXTEND ITS REACH
BEYOND THE SPORT.
WE TALKED TO THE CLUB PRESIDENT NEXT.
DANI: AN ITALIAN SOCCER CLUB IS
LOOKING TO DEVELOP BUSINESSES
THAT EXTEND BEYOND THE FIELD,
MAKING A FRESH PUSH INTO RETAIL.
THE NEW COLLABORATION MODEL
AIMS TO CREATE A LUXURY
PLATFORM FOR GLOBAL SPORTS
CLUBS AND PROPERTIES.
WE ARE JOINED BY THE CLUB
PRESIDENT.
I THINK A LOT OF ESPECIALLY
AMERICAN VIEWERS ARE NOT GOING
TO BE FAMILIAR WITH THE MODEL
YOU ARE BUILDING WITH THE
PLATFORM.
CAN YOU EXPLAIN SOME OF THE
WORK YOU ARE DOING AT THE CLUB?
>> THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
BASICALLY, COMO IS A VERY SMALL
TOWN, LAKE COMO.
THE LAKE IS MORE FAMOUS THAN
OUR SOCCER TEAM.
WE BUILT A CLUB IN THE FOURTH
DIVISION, AND NOW WE ARE IN THE
HIGHEST LEVEL, COMPETING FOR A
SPOT IN THE EUROPEAN
COMPETITION.
YET AT THE SAME TIME, OUR CLUB
IS SO SMALL COMPARED TO OUR
CLOSEST RIVAL, AC MILAN AND
INTER-MILAN.
WE HAVE TO BE CREATIVE TO COME
UP WITH THE REVENUES TO BE ABLE
TO COMPETE WITH THE CLUBS IN
EUROPE BY CREATING OUR OWN
RETAIL INITIATIVES, SPORTS
TOURISM, TRAVEL, SOCCER CAMPS,
AND DIGITAL OFFERINGS.
WE DECIDED WE WANT TO BECOME
THE PREMIUM SPORTS TOURISM
DESTINATION IN THE WORLD. MATT:
IT MAKES SENSE.
I HAVE BEEN LUCKY ENOUGH TO
SPEND SOME TIME IN COMO.
IT IS A WONDERFUL PLACE.
THE BOATS ARE GORGEOUS.
THE CARS ARE AMAZING.
GEORGE CLOONEY LIVES THERE.
JAMES BOND ALWAYS SEEMS TO END
UP THERE.
BUT WHO ARE YOU AIMING THESE
PRODUCTS AT AND HOW ARE YOU
GETTING THAT MESSAGE TO THEM?
>> OUR AUDIENCE IS 40% OUTSIDE
OF COMO ITSELF, AND THE
INTERNATIONAL MARKET.
LOOK -- LAKE COMO'S POPULARITY,
WE HAVE 5.8 MILLION TOURISTS A
YEAR COMING FROM THE U.S., SO
MOST OF OUR MERCHANDISE IS
GOING TO THE U.S.
PARTNERING WITH A U.S.
BRAND ALLOWS US TO ACCELERATE
THAT ADOPTION RATE, SO TO SPEAK.
DANI:
IT IS ALMOST LIKE YOU HAVE A
PRIVATE EQUITY MODEL.
YOU LOOK AT THE CLEARLAKE
VENTURE WHERE THEY OWN CHELSEA,
OWN REAL ESTATE, OWN DIFFERENT
COMMERCIAL ASSETS, BUT ALSO OWN
OTHER CLUBS.
IS THAT THE DIRECTION YOU MIGHT
GO IN, TO DO A MULTI-CLUB
OWNERSHIP TYPE STRATEGY?
>> WE HAVE ENOUGH HEADACHES
MANAGING ONE CLUB, IS THE WAY
WE SEE IT.
WE CREATE A MULTI-CLUB
SERVICING MODEL.
WE SEPARATE COMPANIES INTO
DIFFERENT ENTITIES, BUT THE
RETAIL DIVISION, THE RETAIL
COMPANY, IS SERVICING TODAY
ALMOST 11 OTHER SOCCER CLUBS.
WE CREATE OWNERSHIP THROUGH THE
ROUTE FOR FANS INITIATIVES --
FOOT -- ROOT FOR
FANS INITIATIVES WITH CLUBS IN
THE U.S., ITALY, THE SAUDI
LEAGUE, AND FRANCE AS WELL.
WITH SUCH A LITTLE TOWN, IT IS
EASIER FOR US TO GET REVENUE BY
WORKING WITH OTHER CLUBS AS WE
BUILD OUR OWN. MATT:
WHO ELSE CAN YOU PARTNER WITH?
IT STRIKES ME THAT MY FAVORITE
-- ONE OF MY FAVORITE CAR SHOWS
IS THE VILLA D'ESTE, I THINK
TWO WEEKS FROM TODAY.
IT WOULD MAKE SENSE TO SEE
SOMEONE GETTING OUT OF A
CLASSIC PREWAR BENTLEY, WEARING
YOUR CLOTHES.
>> WE DO HAVE OUR LAKE COMO
BRAND THAT WE ACTUALLY SELL,
AND IT DOES REALLY WELL.
UNLIKE OTHER SUPER CLUBS,
USUALLY MOST CLUBS WOULD HAVE
80%, 90% OF THEIR MERCHANDISING
REVENUE COMING FROM JERSEY
SALES. OURS IS ONLY 38%.
NOW, THROUGH ROOT FOR FANS, NOW
WE ARE TARGETING CLUBS WITH A
BIGGER FAN BASE THAN US.
SO HOPEFULLY WE CAN GROW.
FROM LAST YEAR TO THIS YEAR, I
THINK THE GROWTH WAS 10 X, SO
WE ARE HOPING WE CAN GROW EVEN
FASTER, MOVING ON TO NEXT YEAR.
DANI:
WILL WE SEE GEORGE CLOONEY IN
THE STUDIO NEXT WEARING A ZIP
UP?
>> THAT WOULD BE NICE.
I CAN'T PROMISE THAT.
WE WILL SEE TOMORROW. DANI:
THANK YOU FOR JOINING US.
ENJOY THE REST OF YOUR WEEKEND
IN COMO. I AM QUITE JEALOUS.
A CHECK ON MARKETS AS WE HEAD
TO THE END OF THE HOUR.
WE ARE TRADING AROUND ALL-TIME
HIGHS WITH SOLID EARNINGS
ACROSS THE INDUSTRY.
TODAY, IT IS A BOOST FROM APPLE
AS YIELDS GO NOWHERE AND ENERGY
PRICES FALL.
MONDAY, I'M GOING TO BE AT THE
MILKEN INSTITUTE CONFERENCE.
WE WILL HAVE THE OAKTREE'S CEO
AND PGT PARTNERS CEO.
IT IS GOING TO BE A STACKED
LINEUP. MORE INTERVIEWS TO COME.
IN THE MEANTIME, HAVE A
WONDERFUL WEEKEND.